[MUSIC]
[音乐]
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> Okay, well, welcome to lecture 12 of Stanford CS193P
欢迎来到 CS193P 课程的第12讲
winter of 2015.
这是 CS193P 在2015年冬季的课程
Today we're going to talk about a different kind
今天我们想要聊一些与上周
of animation than we talked about last week,
讲的不一样的动画效果
which is physics-based dynamic animation, it's called.
叫做，物理动态动画效果（Physics-based Dynamic Animation）
And then I'm going to do a big demo of that,
然后我会做一个大的 Demo
which is called Dropit.
这个 Demo 我想称之为 Dropit
First of all, let me say that what we're,
首先
our topic this week is dynamic animation.
我们这周的话题就是动态动画效果
So it's a different kind of animation than we saw
这与我们上周讲到的动画效果
last week.
有相当的不同
It's a physics-based thing.
它是基于物理效果的
Now we're gonna have some fun with it,
因为是与真实世界的物理效果相同
this physics-based thing.
所以我们能够在这上面做一些有趣的事情
And you're gonna write a game with it.
同时，你们会用这个来编写一个游戏
Yeah, I'm not sure you would really use it for that.
当然，我并不确定你肯定会用到它
It's more for things like this.
但是更多类似于这种的东西
You see how when I slide this up,
比如现在，我上拉 Control Center
it kind of bounces a little and wiggles?
在最后的时刻，它会有一个晃动的弹跳效果
See? It doesn't just kind of solid
看到了吗？这个动画并不是
go up and stop, it kind of bounces off the top.
我直接上拉 Control Center，然后它就停止在最高的点上了
Basically what's happening there is that there's gravity
通常，我们会说，这里有一个仿重力
pointing up.
Okay?
明白了吗？
And then there's a little bit of elasticity, and
同时，这里会有一点点的弹性
that view it's just being allowed to fall up and
所以，这个视图被允许向上滑动
bounce off the bottom.
并在到达起顶部的时候有一个弹跳效果
Okay? And that's what we're going to
明白了吗？
learn how to do today is have gravity and bouncing and
这也就是我们今天想要学习的内容，如何让一个视图
all this kind of physics behavior.
拥有类似的重力效果和弹跳效果，等等类似的物理动画效果
But instead of just doing something, you know,
但是，我们并不想通过一些平时很无聊的 Demo 来学习
boring like this, we're going to make a game out of it.
取而代之的是，我们想要通过这个做一个游戏
The game we're going to make is Breakout.
这个游戏我们想称之为 Breakout
Or Brickout, sometimes people call it.
或者有些人喜欢称之为 Brickout
The point is to learn all the APIs of this physics-based
这个游戏的目的是，学习所有基于这个物理动态引擎
dynamic engine.
的 API
But to have some fun along the way, so I've actually made
想要让这个过程是非常有趣的，我制定了
the requirements for the game itself be pretty light, okay?
一部分很小的对游戏的要求
It just basically has to do the basics of the game, and
最基础的是，必须符合游戏的规则
then giving you a lot of room to maneuver on kind of the fun
其他的地方就留给你们自由发挥的空间
features of the game, so.
你们肯定会很喜欢的
So dynamic animation is different
好的，动态动画效果与我们上周
than the animation we talked about last week.
讲的动画效果是不太一样的
Last week, we were talking about taking certain view
上周我们讲的是，取一些特定的视图属性
properties and animating them over time.
并根据时间来让它动起来
Or perhaps animating an entire change to a view
类似于，将一个视图像卡片一样翻转过来的操作
like a flipping over a card by flipping the whole
view over, okay?
Or cross-dissolving the entire view.
还有，Cross-Dissolving 整个视图这样的动画效果
This is more where we're going to have our views, and
但是我们这周讲的是
we're going to have them moving around on screen.
我们如何在屏幕上移动这些视图
Maybe running up against other things and
有可能这些视图于其他的视图之间相互影响
bouncing a little bit, that kind of stuff.
产生一些弹跳效果等类似的东西
The way you make this stuff work, okay,
然而你想做出这样的动画效果
it's a multi-step process.
要经历很多个步骤
The firs thing is,
首先要做的是
you're going to need a UIDynamicAnimator.
你需要一个 UIDynamicAnimator
That's the class that really drives the whole thing, so
这是驱动这些物理动画效果的本源
you need one of those.
所以你需要一个 UIDynamicAnimator 的实例
And you'll only have one for any animation that's going on.
如果你需要一种类似的动画效果，那你就需要一个它的实例
You can have multiple UIDynamicAnimators if you had,
你可以同时有多个 UIDynamicAnimator 的实例
for example, another view doing some animation at
比如，同时有另外的一个视图拥有其他的物理动画效果
the same time.
But within your own view,
但是在你自己的视图里面
you're probably just gonna have this one animator.
你可能只需要一个 UIDynamicAnimator 的实例
So you're gonna create this animator,
首先，你已经创建好了这个 UIDynamicAnimator
then you're gonna add dynamic behaviors to it.
然后你要做的是，向它之上添加一些动态的行为
So behaviors are like gravity and
比如类似于重力的行为
collision and things attached to each other.
或者是碰撞，或是附加在一起的效果
It's how the things inside are going to behave, 'Kay?
这就是你的 UIDynamicAnimator 中的视图相互之间影响的行为，明白了吗？
And these are basically physics-based descriptions of
这就是描述了这些视图物理行为的东西
how they're going to behave.
And then, of course,
当然，接下来
there's the things that are going to be animated,
就是，想要受这些动画影响的视图
which for our purposes are always gonna be UIViews.
目前我们只会用到 UIView 的实例
Okay?
明白了吗？
These UIViews, DynamicItems,
这些视图，Dynamic Items
they are going to be affected by the gravity and
将会受其他对象的重力、碰撞
the collisions and all those things.
或者其他的效果
Okay?
明白了吗？
That's it.
就这些步骤
Just create the dynamic animator,
简单的说，先创建 UIDynamicAnimator 实例
create the behaviors you want and
然后定义你想要的行为
configure them, add the items to the behaviors, bam.
设置受影响的对象，将这些对象加到这个行为中
It'll just start automatically animating.
然后，视图就自动动起来了
And if you remove an item from an behavior,
同样的，当你从一个行为中移走了一个对象
it'll stop animating.
它就停止了它的动画效果
Okay?
明白了吗？
Simple as that.
就是如此的简单
So let's look at the steps.
让我们看一下这些步骤的代码
The first step is you need to create a UIDynamicAnimator,
首先的第一步，创建一个 UIDynamicAnimator 的实例
and the dynamic animators we're going to use,
我们这里想要使用的是 animator 变量
I'm only going to talk about ones that animate views.
这里我们只会使用到视图
You can actually use an animator to animate arbitrary
当然你还可以对一些抽象的东西做动画效果
things.
Okay?
明白了吗？
Not even graphical things.
不一定是要图形上的东西
But we're only gonna talk about animating views.
但是这里我们只会讲到视图的动画
Okay?
明白了吗？
So when we create a dynamic animator that animates views,
我们已经创建了一个 UIDynamicAnimator 来让我们的视图动起来
we have to specify the top-level
我们必须指定最顶层的 UIView
UIView, the view at the top of the view hierarchy where our
也就是在视图系统中最顶层的那个视图
animations are occurring in.
所有动画效果发生在这里面
Now animations can occur anywhere deep
现在，动画效果就可以在视图系统中的任意一个地方
down that view hierarchy you want.
其作用了
But we have specified the top-level view.
所以我们需要指定最顶层的那个视图
So, in other words, any view that this dynamic animator's
换言之，UIDynamicAnimator 所有的动画效果都会
going to animate has to be a subview or subview of
是这个 Reference View 的子视图，或者是子视图的子视图
a subview of a subview of this reference view.
Okay? So that's the only argument
明白了吗？
you have to provide when you create a dynamic animator.
这就是你创建 UIDynamicAnimator 实例唯一需要的参数
Then you create these behaviors.
接下来我们创建一些行为
Behaviors are these concrete subclasses of
行为是一些 UIDynamicBehavior 的子类
UIDynamicBehavior.
And so there's like UIGravityBehavior,
比如说 UIGravityBehavior
just say UIGravityBehavior, takes no arguments.
接受0个参数
And in CollisionBehavior,
在 CollisionBehavior 中
I'm going to talk about all of these behaviors you can do,
我将会讨论所有你能做的行为
and you just add them with the method addBehavior
你只需要使用 addBehavior 来添加它们
to your animator.
到你的动画器（animator）中
Simple enough.
足够简单了吧
And then you add the DynamicItems which are gonna
随后你会在这之上添加 DynamicItem
be UIViews.
它们应该是 UIView
Okay? UIDynamicItems
明白了吗？
are really just a protocol I'm gonna talk about in a second,
我等下会讲，UIDynamicItems 只是一个协议
but UIView implements that protocol.
但是 UIView 实现了这个协议
But you just add these items using the method addItem on
但是你目前不用管这些，你只需要用 UIDynamicBehavior 的 addItem
UIDynamicBehavior.
把这些东西添加进来就可以了
So you see how I'm adding the items to the behavior.
这样你就可以看到我时如何给 item 添加行为的
So you don't add the items to the animator,
不是把这些东西添加到动画器中
you add the items to the behavior.
而是将这些东西添加到行为中
You add the behaviors to the animator.
然后把行为添加到动画器里
Okay?
明白了吗？
So in this case up here, item1,
在这里，item1
I added it to gravity and collider.
我把它添加给了 gravity 和 collider
So item1 is going to be affected by the gravity,
所以 item1 将会受其他对象的重力
and it's also going to collide with whatever
和碰撞的设置所影响
the collider sets up.
Item2, is affected by the gravity, but
item2 将会受其他对象的重力所影响
it will not collide with whatever's in the collider.
但是不会受到碰撞效果的影响
It also won't collide with item1, they would pass right
item2 不会与 item1 相碰撞，它们会相互穿过彼此
through each other, because it's not part of the collider.
因为这不受碰撞效果的影响
Okay, so if you want things to interact with each other,
所以，如果你想要这两者相互产生互动的话
they have to both be a part of the same behavior.
它们都必须添加到一个相同的行为
Okay, that protocol is talking about UIDynamicItems
好的，这个协议讲的是 UIView
that UIView implements.
实现的 UIDynamicItems
It just has three properties, actually, bounds.
它有三个属性，bounds
This is read-only, so
这个属性是只读的
the animator cannot animate the size of something.
动画器无法改变一个东西的大小
Okay? Because
这是因为
the bounds part of the protocol is read-only.
这个协议实现的 bounds 部分是只读的
So the two animatable properties are the center, so
另外两个可以被动画改变的属性是，center
that's the position of the thing.
这定义了一个对象的位置
So you can see animators moving things all over
你可以看到动画效果将对象的位置移动来移动去
the place, that's mostly what they do.
这也就是常用的一些动画
And then also a transform, which is AffineTransform.
还有一个 transform 属性，它是 AffineTransform 类型的
Now notice that view UIView already have
现在，注意到 UIView 已经拥有了这三个属性
all three of these properties, so you didn't even have to
你不需要做任何事情去实现这个协议了
do anything to implement this protocol.
That AffineTransform,
我顺便说一下，这里的 AffineTransform
by the way, is only used for rotation.
是用于旋转的
So basically, the animator can rotate the view, or
大致你可以理解为，这个动画器能够旋转这个视图
he can position it.
或者重新定位这个视图
That's something that the animator can do.
这就是动画器能够做到
Okay, now if you change the center or the transform,
好的，现在，如果你想改变一个视图的中心或者使其变形
like you change the frame or
就像你改变了视图的 frame 或
the center of the view to move it and
视图的中心使其移动位置
the animator has a hold of it, you gotta tell the animator
你告诉拥有这个对象的动画器
you did that by calling updateItemUsingCurrentState.
你使用一个叫做 updateItemUsingCurrentState 的方法
You just pass the view.
传入视图
Okay?
明白了吗？
And so the animator can say, oh, that thing moved.
然后，动画器会知道，这个东西移动了
And it will update its internal state
它会从开始的地方更新内部状态
to start from wherever that thing is.
无论这个东西的位置是哪里
Does that make sense?
我这么说能明白吗？
Obviously, if you and the animator are fighting over
显然的，你和动画器正在争抢
who's positioning a view, you have to at least communicate,
重新定位一个视图的所有权，你需要协调好这个
and this is how you do it.
上面的就是你如何做的过程
Okay?
明白了吗？
Simple enough.
就是如此的简单
All right. So let's talk about some of
好的，让我们再谈谈另外的一些效果
these behaviors, the concrete behavior.
凝聚（concrete）的行为
So gravity is very simple behavior.
重力行为非常的简单
It just has an angle.
就设置一个角度
So you can have the gravity be going up the screen or
之后你就可以在屏幕上看到重力的效果
down the screen or to the left or to the right or
无论是从左到右的重力效果还是
any angle you want, and it has a magnitude.
你想要的任意的角度
Okay? So
明白了吗？
the magnitude is in the scale where 1.0 is 1,000
这里的大小（magnitude）的比例是 1.0:1000
points per second per second.
1000 像素点每二次方秒
'Kay?
You all know that gravity is an acceleration.
你们都知道重力是一种加速度
The acceleration due to gravity on Earth is 9.8
这个加速度在地球上是 9.8 米每平方秒
meters per second squared.
And the acceleration due to gravity in these behaviors is
这里的重力加速度是 1000 点每平方米秒
1,000 points per second squared.
'Kay? You can also set this
明白了吗？当然你可以用一个向量设置
as a vector, but angle and magnitude
但是角度和大小
are probably the easiest way to understand this.
会是一个最简单的弄懂它的方法
So you just set the gravity.
只要设置好重力
Now any item you add will start accelerating in
任意的对象在这个方向上就有一个加速度
that direction.
The instance you add it,
你添加的那个实例
it's gonna start accelerating in that direction,
会在这个方向上有一个加速度
just like gravity were pulling on it.
就好像重力正在拉它的样子
'Kay?
Then there's attachment behaviors.
还有一些附属（attachment）行为的动画效果
So attachments you can attach two items, or
对于附属行为，你可以添加两个对象
you can attach an item to an anchor point.
或者将这两个对象添加到同一个锚点
Okay? That item still going to be
明白了吗？这个东西仍旧会被其他的动作所影响
affected by all the other behaviors like gravity, so
比如说重力
if I attached a view.
但是，当我将一个视图，附属
To an anchor point, like this.
到一个锚点，就像这样
And there was gravity on the view.
由于这个视图上有重力的影响
It would swing down like this and
它会像这样摆动下来
stop if there was gravity down, right?
然后停止，就像重力的作用那样
'Cuz the gravity would be pulling it down.
因为重力正在拉这个视图
But the attachment would be holding onto it.
但是附属却是保持的效果
Does that make sense?
我这么说能明白吗？
So the attachment basically.
所以说，附属的行为基本上是
But it's like a bar that's attached.
好比附着在一个栏（bar）上
That bar could be springy also.
这个栏是有弹性的
So if it was a springy bar attachment, then the gravity
如果是附属在一个弹性的栏上，那么重力会把这个视图向下拉
would pull it down, and it would spring like this.
然后这个视图会在栏附近弹来弹去
So you can get a little springy and
你可以得到一个小小的弹性效果
you can control the dampening and all that as well.
而且你可以控制这个弹性效果反馈的程度
You can also control the distance between
同样可以控制这两个东西之间的距离
those two things.
By the way, that distance is settable while it's animating,
顺便说一句，这个距离在进行动画的时候还是可以设置的
so this thing might be pulling down and
比方说，这个东西正在被往下拉的时候
you might be changing the length and
你改变了它的长度
it might swing way down and
这样它就会向下摆动
then you might pull it back up.
接着，你有可能向上拉动了一下，它就会向上摆动
So you can control all this stuff.
你可以控制这一切
All these things like that,
类似这样的东西
even the anchor point can move while it's animating.
甚至说是，锚点在进行动画的时候都是可以被改变的
And we're gonna actually do that in the demo.
我们会在 Demo 里实现一下
So it's incredibly flexible what you can do when you
所以在动画进行的过程中
can change the attributes of these behaviors on the fly,
这些属性都是非常自由可调节的
while things are happening with gestures or whatever.
当涉及到手势或者其他类似的东西时
Collision behavior is an awesome behavior.
碰撞效果就非常起作用了
You're gonna use that very often.
你会在之后频繁地使用它
It can basically control collisions between items.
它能够控制对象之间的碰撞
And also, between items and a boundary.
还可以控制对象和一个边界之间的碰撞
And you can set up as many boundaries as you want.
这里的意思是，你可以设置类似的多个边界
So, for your assignment five,
所以，你们的作业五
where you're gonna be doing this brickout game or
你会做一个叫 Brickout 或者是 Breakout 的游戏
breakout game.
You're probably gonna wanna use boundaries for
你大概会为你的砖头用到边界这个属性
all your bricks.
You're not gonna, they'll be UI views cuz you've got to
由于它们是 UIView，所以你需要手动绘制出它们
draw them, but you won't be having those UI views
但是你不希望这些视图参与到碰撞效果之中去
participate in the collisions, cuz then the bricks would
因为这些砖最后会相互之间飞来飞去，满屏幕都是
start flying into each other, all over the place.
You just want them to kind of be fixed boundaries, so
你想要的，应该是一个固定的边界
that when the ball hits them,
当球击中它们的时候
then that view animates itself disappearing, okay?
某个砖的边界才会消失，然后触发碰撞效果，明白了吗？
So the way you set these boundaries,
所以你设置这些边界
there's really two ways.
这里会有两个方法
One is you can set a Bezier path, any Bezier path, and it
一个是，你可以设置一个 UIBezierPath，任意一种贝塞尔曲线
will use that Bezier path as the outer edges of a boundary.
然后，它会使用这个贝塞尔曲线当作它的外部边界
'Kay.
明白了吗？
It could be a rectangle or a circle, could be a line.
它可以是一个矩形或者是一个圆形，甚至是一条直线
And you just, things that hit the line bounce off of it.
你只需要，当东西碰到它的时候，弹回去
Or you can set this translatesReferenceBoundsInto-
或者你可以设置 translatesReferenceBoundsIntoBoundary
Boundary, set that to true, and then the outer edges
方法，设置它为真，然后
of the animated reference view will be a boundary.
动画对象的所有的外边框，就会变成一个边界
Now, you can't use that for your homework,
你在你的作业中不能使用它
because of course, the bottom one has to fall through.
因为，最底下的那个砖必须是掉下来的
If your bouncing ball gets past the paddle, it falls off.
如果你的球穿过去了，它会掉下来
So you'll have to use lines.
这里你只能使用贝塞尔曲线中的线段
Bezier curve that's line two,
线段的贝塞尔曲线
line two, line two or whatever.
Okay? When you add a boundary
明白了吗？当你添加一个边界的时候
you give it an identifier.
你要给它一个标识符
Now, that identifier is an NSCopying.
这里的标识符是一个遵循 NSCopying 协议的对象
So NSCopying is a protocol that is implemented by
NSCopying 是一个协议，被 NSString
NSString, NSNumber,
NSNumber 所实现的
things like that, so that means String and
其他的类也可能实现了这个协议，但是这代表
Int/Double also can be used as the identifier for a boundary.
String 类型和 Int/Double 类型都可以作用一个边界的标识符
So when you hit a boundary you get this message.
当你触碰到一个边界的时候，你会得到这个消息
You want to se yourself to be the UI collision behaviors
你想要在碰撞的行为中设置你自己为代理
delegate.
And when a boundary is hit, it will send this message,
当一个边界被触及的时候，它会发送这个消息
it actually has a few other messages,
事实上，还有另外一些消息代理可以发送的
to its delegates saying, there was a collision
当一个对象和一个边界发生碰撞的时候
between an item and a boundary or between two items.
或者是两个对象之间发生的时候
And it's going to pass back that boundary identifier.
代理将会传递这个标识符
You see that boundary identifier, so
你看到这里第三个参数了吗？
the third argument there in this
“边界的标识符”（BoundaryIdentifier）
method that it's gonna call in its delegate, and
它会在代理中去调用这个东西
you have to cast that thing, cuz it'll be an NSCopying.
因为这是一个遵循 NSCopying 协议的对象，所以你需要做一个类型转换
So you got to cast it to be a string or number or
所以你将它转换成一个字符串或者是一个数字
whatever you put in, cast it to be that back.
这么说吧，你设置标识符的参数是什么类型的，这里你就转换成什么类型的
Okay?
明白了吗？
So it's a little small thing to understand is that
这里你需要明白一点点类型转换的东西
casting behavior.
Okay?
So that's simple collisions.
这是简单的碰撞效果
The snap behavior is used a lot in UI.
在用户交互中，Snap 行为经常被使用到
You won't be using this in your homework but
但是你在这个作业中并不会使用到它
it's actually used a lot.
但在其他地方，它经常会被使用
It's essentially, you could imagine that you set up four
而且是很基本的。
springs on the corner of a view in a new location.
你可以想象，你在屏幕的四个角设置了弹性效果
The thing will fly to that space
当这个对象移动到空间的另外一个位置的时候
in the middle of the four springs and
发生了碰撞
then the springs will kind of oscillate.
然后这个弹性效果就会触发类似于震荡一样的效果
So snap behavior is basically,
举例说，Snap 行为
move to here, with a little bit of oscillation.
移到某个地方，发生了碰撞
Okay, boing, kind of snapping.
然后震荡。这就是 Snap 行为
Okay, but
明白了吗？
snapping in a way that doesn't disconcert the user,
但是 Snap 行为在某种程度上说，它并不会让用户分心
where things just like, moving.
因为东西就像，移动
It flies across the screen, and then wiggles a little bit.
然后摇动了一下下
So let the user know,
所以，用户知道
there's a little thing just got positioned here.
东西已经到了这个位置了
So, you just specify the point you want it to snap to, and
实现这个，你只需要指定你想要 Snap 到的点
the item you want to snap, and it will zoom over there.
以及，哪个对象你想要产生 Snap 动作，就够了
Okay, and you can control how much the springs spring.
同样你可以控制这个震荡的效果
Is it a big movement or just kinda a small movement?
是一个比较大的振幅呢还是一个比较小的振幅
You can control the damping with that
通过同样设置这里的 damping 属性
property there, damping.
Then there's a push behavior.
另外，还有一个 Push 行为
A push behavior means push on this thing in a certain
一个 Push 行为，代表的意思是，把这个东西推向一个特定的角度
angle and magnitude, kind of like gravity.
或者是一个力度，有点类似于重力
The big difference between push and
但是 Push 和重力效果最大的区别就是
gravity, two differences.
两个地方
One, a push can be a one time push, all right.
一个是，Push 行为可以是一个一次性的效果
Just instantaneous push, or it can be a continuous push
也可以是一个持续性、连续的效果
which is not like gravity cuz it's not accelerating.
不像重力的地方是，它并不会加速
It's just a continuous velocity.
它是以一个恒定的速度
Okay? You understand the difference
明白了吗？
between acceleration and velocity.
你明白加速度和速度之间的区别吗？
So push would be, if you had a continuous push it would be
如果你有一个持续性的 Push 行为
a constant velocity.
那么被 Push 的对象会有一个恒定的速度
Okay?
Now one thing about push behavior that's interesting is
另外一个关于 Push 行为的很有意思的事情是
when you push, you add this behavior to your animator,
当你 Push 的时候，你把这个行为添加到你的动画器中
it'll cause the items that are in it to be pushed.
它会影响所有被添加到这个动画器里的东西
And then it just kind of sits around there.
然而它并没有任何实质性的功能
Wasted if it's not a continuous push.
白白占用我们的资源，如果它不是一个持续性的 Push 行为的话
And sits there, wasting memory.
And I'm going to talk about in a few slides how we can
我会在之后的一些幻灯片中谈到这个问题
get that memory back.
如何拿回这些占用的资源
Okay, and we'll have to do a little memory cycle
好的，这里我们还需要做一个小小的内存循环保护
protection there.
Now, there's a special kind of behavior,
有一种非常特别的行为
called a dynamic item behavior.
称作动态对象行为
Don't be confused by dynamic behavior,
不要被动态行为（Dynamic Behavior）这个词所迷惑
which is the super class of all behaviors.
这是所有行为的父类
And dynamic item behavior,
动态行为
which is a sub-class of UIDynamicBehavior.
本身是一个 UIDynamicBehavior 的子类
Item behavior says how does this item or
对象行为描述了被添加这个行为的对象
any of the items added to this behavior,
或者是一些对象是怎么样的
how do they behave when other behaviors make them interact?
它们会和另外的一些行为如何交互
So this is when something smashes into a wall in
举例来说，如果一个东西撞到一个墙上
a collider, in a collision behavior, how springy is it?
这是一个碰撞效果，然而它的弹性程度是怎么样的？
Can it spin?
这个东西能够旋转吗？
Okay?
Or does it have to stay un-rotated?
或者说，它是不是应该保持角度不做旋转？
Those kind of things
如此如此的这一些东西
are all specified by this UIDynamicItemBehavior.
都由这个 UIDynamicItemBehavior 所指定
So very often you'll have a gravity behavior,
通常来说，你会有一个重力行为
a collider behavior.
一个碰撞行为
You'll also have a dynamic
你还会需要一个动态对象行为
item behavior to describe how much springiness is.
来描述这个的弹性程度
You can, it also does density,
你还可以描述密度
resistance, other things I haven't mentioned here.
强度，或者另外一些这里我没有提及的东西
You can look in the documentation.
都可以在文档里找到
But it's kind of all the things you would expect if you
然而，当你需要一个物理引擎的时候，你才需要了解这些东西
had a physics-based engine, you need to set the kind of
你需要设置所有这些属性
attributes, the physical attributes of an item.
对象的物理属性
This dynamic item behavior also can report to you
动态对象行为还可以告诉你
the current linear velocity and
当前对象的线速度
angular velocity of this item.
和角速度
So at any time, if you want to know,
任意时刻都可以获取到
how fast is this thing moving and in what direction?
这样你就可以知道这个东西移动多块、什么方向
You can get its linear velocity.
通过获取其线速度
Or if you want to know how fast is this thing is
而你可以知道这个东西是否在旋转
spinning, if at all, you can get its angular velocity.
通过获取其角速度
And you can also add velocity to it in a certain direction.
甚至说，你还可以在一个特定的方向上添加一个速度
So if you had something that was moving, and
我们假想一下，你有一个正在移动的东西
you wanted to stop it, you could.
你想让它停下，你可以添加一个反方向的速度
And then if you wanted to continue,
如果你想要让停止的对象继续运动
you could add the velocity back.
你把这个速度加回来
Just saying is all.
就是如此
Okay.
好的
So that's a dynamic behavior.
这就是动态行为
Now, that's dynamic item behavior.
现在，这是动态对象行为
Now here's UIDynamicBehavior.
这里是 UIDynamicBehavior
This is the superclass of all of these behaviors.
是所有这些行为的父类
And it's kind of an interesting superclass,
这是一个很有趣的父类
because you can actually create a subclass.
因为，你可以创建一个其子类
And in the invitation of the subclass you add
在创建的子类中，你可以添加子行为
child behaviors, you add other behaviors so
你可以添加其他的行为
you can have a composite behavior.
这样你就可以拥有一个复合行为
This is very common to do.
这是非常常见的做法
When you have three or
当在一个相同集合的对象中
four different behaviors all working on the same set
你想对它们所有添加三个或者是四个的行为
of items.
A lot of times,
经常
you'll create a subclass in UI dynamic behavior, and in
你会选择创建一个 UIDynamicBehavior 的子类
the init method, you'll call this method addChildBehavior,
在初始化方法中，你调用这个方法 addChildBehavior
and you'll add a gravity of collider, item behavior.
你可以添加一个重力、碰撞或者是动态对象行为
You see what I mean?
你知道我的意思了吗？
You'll add them as child behaviors.
你可以将它们添加为子行为
And now, this behavior will do all the things that those
现在，这个行为就达到所有你添加的行为的效果了
behaviors did.
Okay? So,
明白了吗？
you'll have a kind of a big combined behavior.
所以，你会拥有一个非常庞大的行为
And I'll do that in the demo, so
我会在 Demo 里演示一下
you can see what that looks like.
你可以知道具体是怎么操作的
All behaviors, know the dynamic animator they're in.
接下来，所有的行为
And a behavior can only be in one dynamic animator at
一次只能在一个动画器中
a time.
So it has a property called dynamicAnimator.
这里有一个称作 dynamicAnimator 的属性
And it's read-only.
只读的
And it will tell you.
它会告诉你这些
You can ask a collider who's animating
你可以询问一个碰撞行为谁正在进行动画效果
right now, and it will tell you that the dynamicAnimator
它会返回给你正在动画的 dynamicAnimator
is animating it.
Also, all dynamic behaviors will be sent
同样，当所有的动态行为被移动到另外一个不同的动画器中
the message will be moved to animator
它们将会发送一个消息
when they are going to switch to a different animator.
willMovedToAnimator
Especially this is switching form not having an animator
尤其是从没有动画器中切换到有动画器的时候
to having one.
Or from having one to not having one anymore.
或者是从有动画器中切换到没有动画器的时候
Okay?
明白了吗？
That should be UIDynamicAnimator,
这里会有一个问号，所以是一个可选类型的
question mark, that's an optional.
UIDynamicAnimator
Okay? Cuz it might be said,
明白了吗？因为我们可能会这么调用
will move to animator nil,
willMoveToAnimator(nil)
which means you're being taken out of an animator.
也就是说，我们从一个动画器中移除它
Okay, very important property on UIDynamicBehavior called
在 UIDynamicBehavior 里，有一个非常重要的属性叫
action.
action
Action is a function, takes no arguments, returns nothing.
action 是一个没有参数的函数，并且不返回值
99.999% of the time it's set with a closure, okay?
99.999% 的情况下，它通过一个闭包来设值
And this piece of code will be executed every time this
然后，每次这个行为发生在其对象上的时候
behavior acts upon its items.
这一小段代码都会执行
'Kay?
That means it's called a lot.
这代表，这个方法会被多次调用
Okay?
明白了吗？
Imagine a gravity behavior,
想象一个重力行为
it's constantly accelerating something.
它以一个恒定的加速度在加速一个对象
So it's constantly acting upon it.
也就是说它持续地 “act”
So it's constantly gonna be calling this.
所以它持续地调用这个方法
So whatever code you put here,
无论你放在闭包里是什么样的代码，它都会持续调用
an action wants to be really efficient, okay?
一个 action 要做到非常高效
It wants to be very small, very compact.
同时长度需要非常短小精悍
This is a place to do some optimization,
这里是需要做一些优化的
have a data structure where you can store things, so
比如用一个数据结构去保存一些参数
you don't have to calculate things so much.
以至于你不需要重新计算它们
Cuz this is going to get called a lot, all right?
因为切记，这会被多次调用
And you'll want your animations to be smooth,
你想要你的动画效果非常的顺畅
you don't want them to be bogged down with something
你不希望它们在每一次交互的时候
heavy going on every single time it interacts, okay?
都进行大量的运算，然后卡住不动了
One thing to be careful about this action method,
关于 action 方法需要非常小心的一点是
is that it is a property on the behavior, so
这是行为上的一个属性
if that action method's code refers to the behavior,
所以如果 action 的代码里参考了这个行为的话
you're going to have a memory cycle, and
你会形成一个 retain cycle
so you need to do that unowned thing,
你需要将参考的类型编程 unowned
the capture list that we were taking about.
我们在捕获列表里讨论过这个
You have to do that to break the memory cycle, this is
你需要用捕获列表打破 retain cycle
the case where you've got a property on an object and
这个技术通常是用于，当你对一个对象中有一个属性的时候
the implementation of the closure that you assign often
而且你对这个属性赋值一个闭包，这个闭包的实现中你通常
refers back to the property.
又参考这个属性本身
To the thing that the property is on,
so be careful about that,
所以对这个小心点
let me show you a quick demo about that in a slide or two.
这个我稍后会快速做一个 Demo 给你们了解一下
The UIDynamicAnimator, it also has a delegate.
UIDynamicAnimator 同时拥有一个代理对象
Just like the CollisionBehavior
就像碰撞行为一样
has a delegate, the animator has a delegate, and
动画器有一个代理对象
it'll tell you only two things.
它会告诉你两件事情
It'll tell you when the animation has reached stasis.
首先，它会告诉你动画器是否已经停止
In other words, none of the behaviors need to do anything.
换言之，没有另外的行为会继续产生了
Okay?
明白了吗？
Nothing is happening in the animator.
没有东西会在动画器中发生了
Everything is still, and
所有的对象都是出于静止的状态
then it'll tell you when that's changed.
同样的，当这些改变的时候，它同样会告诉你
Okay? And now, things
当它告诉你的时候
are animating again.
这代表，对象又动起来了
So every time it pauses, it'll tell you.
所以，每一次动画暂停的时候，它都会告诉你
And then, every time it continues, it'll tell you.
每一次动画继续的时候，它也会告诉你
So that way you can tell what's going on.
通过这种方式，你能知道正在发生什么事情
When you design something that uses this stuff is,
当你设计利用这个功能的时候
you want it to reach stasis.
你想要它停止
You don't ever want it to be just constantly
你不想要它始终在动画
animating, right?
对吧？
You want it to try and reach stasis, if possible.
你想要它在可能的情况下，达到静止状态
'Kay, now there might be cases where you actually
另外，还有一种情况，这种情况下
are constantly animating, something's spinning, and
你想要你的动画是持续性的，就像什么东西旋转一样
it's constantly spinning.
你希望它一直保持旋转
Okay, but you wanna design the system, unless that's really
你想要设计这个系统，除非你执意不要
what you intend, you don't want things, classic one is.
不想要这些东西，你想用一个比较传统的做法
You have something with CollisionBehaviors.
你有一些个碰撞效果
The thing flies off screen outside of the collision area,
当对象越过屏幕边缘，越过碰撞区域的时候
and then now it's flying off into outer space, and
他向外层的空间飞过去
it's gonna continue to animate forever
它会持续动画，直到它飞过上千万的 point
as it flies billions of points away, okay.
It's never gonna stop, so you got to be careful about that.
它永远不会停止，这是你需要关心的情况
When things go outside of the area that you're animating,
当对象在你动画区域之外发生的时候
they don't stop animating.
它们并不会停止动画
You need to notice that and
你需要注意到这个问题
take that thing out of the behaviors, so that they're no
然后你需要从这些对象上移除这些行为
longer being accelerated off into nowhere or whatever.
好让它们不再被持续加速了
Okay?
明白了吗？
So be careful about that.
所以关心一下这个点
That can happen in your assignment, of course.
在你们的作业中可能会发生这样的事情
Because the bouncing ball goes off the bottom,
因为当一个弹性的小球越过底部的时候
it'll just keep going.
它就会一直保持动画
Okay? Keep getting animated and
一直一直
never reach stasis.
永远不会达到一个停止的状态
Unless you notice that and
除非你意识到这个问题
take the ball out of the view hierarchy probably.
并且将小球从视图体系中移走
And also away from the behaviors.
同样也从行为中移走
By the way, don't ever put a view into a behavior,
这里我想另外说一句，永远不要将一个视图放在一个行为中
okay, when that view is not on the view hierarchy
好的，当一个视图不在动画器的参考视图的视图体系中
of the reference view of the animator.
Obviously, the animator wants to animate the thing, and
很明显的，动画器想要让某个对象动起来
if it's not in its view hierarchy, like it's in any
如果某个对象不在它的视图体系中
view hierarchy or it's in a different one,
比如某个对象在不同的一个视图体系中
the animator will basically crash your program and
这个动画器就会使你的程序崩溃
I tried to animated something,
永远不要对不在你的视图体系中的对象进行动画操作
it's not in my view hierarchy anywhere.
So don't do that.
不要这么做
Also, don't animate things that are size 00.
同样，不要对一个大小为 (0,0) 的对象动画
Okay.
明白了吗？
It really doesn't make and
这么做非常的不合理
sense to do that because it's not visible anyway,
因为它并不是一个可见的对象
but don't do that.
所以不要尝试这么做
Animator doesn't like that either.
动画器也是如此
All right, quick sample here of memory cycle avoidance.
好的，另外这里有一个 retain cycle 的样例
I was talking about that action method.
还记得我之前讲过的 action 方法吗？
So here, I'm creating a pushBehavior, and
这里，我创建一个 Push 行为
I told you the pushBehavior,
我之前说过
if it's instantaneous, it just sits around.
如果不是持续性的话会没有任何的效果
Because the way you make a push happen is
你真正实现一个 Push 动画应该是
you create a pushBehavior, and you add it to an animator.
创建一个 Push 行为，然后添加到一个动画器
As soon as you add it, it's gonna push any of its items.
只要你一添加，它就会推动任何一个对象
Okay?
明白了吗？
Well, after it's done, if it's an instantaneous push, not
如果这个动画完成的话，如果这不是一个持续性的 Push
continuous, but instantaneous, well, it just sits there.
这些东西就会停止
Cuz it's been added to the animator.
但是由于 Push 行为被添加到了一个动画器
So it's just wasting space.
所以它只会白白浪费空间
So one of the way you can do this is in the pushBehavior's
有一个方法可以让你在 Push 行为中的 action 方法做的
action, which I told you is called whenever the behavior
换言之，也就是每次这个行为在一个对象上被调用的时候
acts on something.
So after the pushBehavior acts and instantaneously pushes,
所以当一个 Push 行为非持续性推动的时候
well, you could just remove the thing from its animator.
你将它从一个动画器中移除
And I told you every behavior knows the animator it's in, so
我告诉过你，每一个行为都知道它属于哪个动画器
that's easy you can just do that one
所以这里并不难做到
line of code in yellow there, pushBehavior, dynamicAnimator,
这里黄色行的代码，pushBehavior.dynamicAnimator!
removeBehavior, pushBehavior myself, okay.
pushBehavior.dynamicAnimator!.removeBehavior(pushBehavior)
But in that closure, I'm referring to myself,
在这个闭包中参考了对象自身
pushBehavior because removing myself, okay.
即 pushBehavior
I'm also referring to myself because I'm getting my
另外我参考自身是因为我正在获取我自己的 dynamicAnimator
own dynamicAnimator.
So this is bad.
这样做是很糟的
This is gonna cause a memory cycle here because
这会在闭包中产生一个 retain cycle
that action closure.
Right? It is gonna stay in memory,
对吗？它会一直呆在内存里
because the action property is pointing to it.
因为 action 属性指向了它
And this push behavior is gonna stay in memory,
另外这个 Push 行为也会保留在内存中
because that closure is pointing to it.
因为这个闭包正在指向它
So since they're both pointing to each other,
当它们两个互相引用的时候
there's always gonna be a pointer to them.
它们之间始终有一个指针指向对方
They'll always stay in memory forever.
所以它们就会永远呆在内存中了
And I mean forever and ever.
注意我这里用的词是“永远”
Okay? If you can't,
明白了吗？
no way to get rid of them.
没有打破这个循环引用关系的方式
So how do we fix that?
如何修复这个问题？
We put that unowned in there.
我们在这里写上 unowned
So we put this capture list here, say that pushBehavior
我们在这里放置一个捕获列表
inside my closure is unowned, meaning don't capture it.
表示，Push 行为在我的闭包中是不会被强引用的，所以不要捕获它
I promise that it will be there when you want to use it,
“我保证这个指针在你想使用的时候都是有效且存在的”
Mr. Closure says.
Mr. 闭包这么说
You do not have to capture it and keep it in memory.
你不需要捕获并在内存中保存它
Okay? And we know that's fine.
明白了吗？我们只要知道这么做没问题
Because obviously, the action wouldn't even be called if
因为很明显的，如果视图的 Push 行为都不存在的时候
the view's pushBehavior didn't exist.
action 永远不会被调用
So this is good.
这就很不错
This code's for sure going to work.
这段代码肯定能正常运行
Okay? You have to do this a lot
你将来会在 action 中经常这么做
with actions.
And you'll probably have to do this in your assignment,
另外你们可能会在你们的作业中会用到这个
when you use an action.
Okay? And I encourage you to try and
我鼓励你去尝试
make your pushBehavior do this as well.
并让你的 Push 行为这么做
It's not a required task, but get your pushBehavior to clean
这不是一个必需的要求，但是这可以让你的 Push 行为
itself up after it's done pushing.
在完成它的使命之后自己清理干净自己
All right, so let's do this demo.
好的，让我们开始 Demo
Any questions about all that?
对以上的东西还有什么疑问吗？
Again, feel free to interrupt me.
再说一遍，请不要害怕打断我，勇敢提出问题
Coming up this week, Friday, we're going to learn
这个周五，我们想要
about the Parse framework, which is a way to
学习解析框架
basically store your data on the network.
这是你处理网络数据的基础
So for if you're building some sort of final project, or
如果你已经在着手做大作业了
you wanna back end or something,
或者需要后端处理
Parse is really simple, nice asynchronous using blocks.
Parse 是一个非常简单的，使用异步 block
Closure's a way to do that.
方式处理的
And then next week,
下一周
we're gonna talk about a variety of topics.
我们将讨论多个问题
We're finally gonna talk about modal segue way a little bit
最后会讨论些模态的 segue
and the application life cycle.
还有应用程序生命周期
And core motion,
还有 Core Motion
which is the gyro and accelerometer and that stuff.
陀螺仪，加速器之类的东西
Okay?
I believe we'll have just enough time for this demo.
我认为剩下的时间够做这个 demo
If I run a little long, you guys know what to do.
如果我时间花得久了些，你们知道该怎么做
So let's start here.
从这开始
Create new project.
创建一个新工程
We always use single view in this class,
单视图应用
we'll call it DropIt.
起名为 DropIt
We're dropping some things.
我们将会往下掉落些东西
I'll put it in the same place we always put it.
把它放在这里
Here we go.
好了
Now I'm going to clean up this stuff.
把工程清理一下
Okay, I don't need this view controller, I'm going to have
我不需要这个视图控制器
a custom view controller, we're not gonna use the one.
我需要一个自定义的
I don't like the name of this, I'm not gonna use.
我不喜欢这个名字
This one.
我不会用这个
My story board right here, I'm going to right off
这个是 StoryBoard
the bat create a new subclass for my view controller.
我现在新建一个视图控制器的子类
So it's going to be a UIViewController.
类型是 UIViewController
I'm gonna call it DropitViewController.
起名为 DropitViewController
Probably could have renamed that other thing.
应该给它起个更好听的名字
It probably would have been just as good.
不过这个也行
So here's Dropit.
好了
I'm gonna get rid of all this in here.
把这些去掉
In my storyboard, let's set the class here to be Dropit.
在 storyboard 中，把类设置为 Dropit
The only UI that my Dropit is gonna have is a custom view,
在 Dropit 中唯一的 UI 会是一个自定义视图
and actually, I'm gonna start out with a generic view.
我先创建一个一般的视图
In your homework assignments, you might be able to get away,
在作业里你们可能会用别的方式
depending on how you architect things, with the generic
取决于你们怎样通过一般的视图来包含砖块还有球
view here to contain your bricks and bouncing ball.
来搭建界面
So I'm going to have this.
所以我使用一般视图
I'm gonna make sure that my constraints are set here.
设置一下约束
So let's Reset to Suggested Constraints.
使用建议的约束
I always like to check them,
在这里检查一下
make sure there's no magic numbers or anything.
确保没有任何魔法数字
That all looks good to me.
看起来还可以
I'm gonna create a outlet to this thing, right there.
为它创建 outlet
I'm gonna call that my game view, so this is going to be
把它叫做 gameView
the view that contains my little Dropit game.
这就是包含 Dropit 这个小游戏的 View
It's not much of a game, but kind of a game.
算不上游戏，但也有点游戏的意思
All right, so there we go.
好的
So, what is my Dropit going to do here?
Dropit 将要做些什么呢
It's going to, along the top of my view, I'm
在视图的顶部
going to drop little squares, okay, right along the top.
我会向下掉落小方块
So first let's just get them dropped along the top.
所以首先，先让它从顶部掉落砖块
And then I'm going to add some gravity, and
为它们添加重力效果
they're going to drop and fall.
让它们掉落下来
Okay? That's why
they're called drops.
这就是起名为 drops 的原因
They're going to fall down.
它们将会掉落
So I'm gonna put these drops along the top, and
先让它们在顶部显示
then later we'll add some gravity.
随后添加重力效果
So let's go ahead and do the, putting them along the top
现在开始做这些
first, pretty straightforward to do.
把它们放到上边
So, I'm going to have the drops be evenly spaced along
现在开始设置方块的尺寸之类的
the top, and I'm going to have a public variable, or
我设置一个公有变量
whatever you want to call it, called dropsPerRow.
起名为 dropsPerRow
It's just gonna be an integer that says how many of these
是一个整型的
little squares go across the top.
表示在顶部有多少方块
And so I'll do ten but I can set it to whatever I want.
先设置为10，也可以设置为任何数值
I like my UI to be configurable.
我希望我的 UI 是可以调整的
Of course in your homework you're gonna want that because
在你们的作业里，你们也得这么做
part of your homework is to add a settings panel, but
因为因为需要一个设置界面
you set a lot of configurable things.
设置一些可以调整的东西
So you want to design your code to not be hard-coded all
你不能一直把代码写得这么死
the time.
So here I'm going to make this to be number I can set.
所以在这里我把它调整一个可以设置的数
And that lets me have a drop size, okay,
再来一个变量，dropSize
which is going to be the size of each drop.
是每一个方块的尺寸
And I'm gonna calculate that as well.
这是通过计算得到的
I'm gonna have it be a calculator property,
它是一个计算属性
based on this dropsPerRow.
基于 dropsPerRow 的
I'm gonna have it be square.
它们都是方块
So we'll have the width and height be the same.
所以长和宽都是相同的
And I'm gonna make it equal to the gameView's bounds
让它等于
dot size dot width, divided by the dropsPerRow.
gameView.bounds.size.width 除以 dropsPerRow
So I'm just gonna take my width,
取出游戏视图的宽
available width of my view, and just divide it up evenly,
除以一共有的方块的数量
so that the drops exactly fill the space.
方块就能完整地填满
And so now I can return a CGSize that
现在我就可以返回一个 CGSize
is both this width and this height.
包含相同的长和宽
Okay, so now I know my drop size.
现在我知道了 dropSize
I'm going to add a gesture, which is the tap gesture.
现在添加一个单击手势
When I put a tap gesture,
当我单击的时候
I'm gonna put one of these drops into my view.
我就在视图中放入个方块
So let's do that.
开始实现
Let's go here to drag and
向视图中
drop gesture out here, tap gesture right here.
拖入一个单击手势
So I'm gonna drag this on here, and
放到这里
bring up my document outline.
打开 document outline
Here's my tap gesture right here.
这里是单击手势
So I'm gonna control drag.
CTRL-拖动
I'm gonna call this gesture drop.
把它起名为 drop
It's a good name cuz that's what it does.
这是一个好名字，因为这表明它完成的动作
It drops one of these things.
它会向下掉落一个方块
Connect it. So here it is.
连接，好了
I could put the code to do all the dropping here, but
我可以把所有的掉落代码写在这里
I'm actually going to put it in another method.
但实际上我会在另一个方法中实现
Call drop.
叫做 drop
Just because it's not necessarily something
因为不止单击手势可以
that could only be done by gesture.
激活向下掉落
Maybe programmatically one could drop things as well.
也许你还会通过代码来向下掉落
So I don't really want to put inside that gesture.
所以我不想把它放到手势操作里
So all the gesture you're gonna do is do this drop.
手势需要做的就是这个 drop 方法
The drop just needs to figure out where the drop is,
drop 方法需要做的时，计算 drop 的位置
so let's get, actually let's make more space here first.
先弄出一些空间
This, I need a lot more space than that.
需要大一点地方
Okay, so we need to figure out where the drop is.
需要弄清楚方块的位置
So I'm going to make it's frame, which is really easy.
创建它的 frame，很简单
I'm just gonna first of all,
首先
create one that is at zero, zero.
我现在0，0点创建一个
Use this nice CGPointZero by the way, which is zero, zero.
使用 CGPointZero 参数为0，0
And the size is, of course, our dropSize.
size 当然是 dropSize
So now I've got drop at zero, zero.
现在在0，0点有了一个方块
And now, I move it along somewhere along there.
现在把它移动到别处
So, I'm gonna move it to frame dot origin dot x equals
令它的 frame.origin.x
CGFloat dot random, dropsPerRow.
等于 CGFloat.random(dropsPerRow)
And you're probably like whoa, CGFloat dot random,
你可能会说，哇，CGFloat.random
you didn't tell me about that cool function.
你没有跟我讲过这个很酷的方法
Well, that's because there's no such function, but
这是因为没有这个函数
I'm gonna write that function right now, really quick.
我现在来快速实现这个函数
There it is.
好了
Okay?
So all it does is,
这就是它做的事情
it just uses arc4random to create a random float
使用 arc4random 创建一个随机的 float
between zero and one less than this maximum.
在0和最大值之间
So here I'm gonna get a random float between zero and
在这我得到了一个在0和dropsPerRow-1之间
dropsPerRow minus one.
的一个随机的 float
Okay, that's cool.
很酷吧
And then I'm gonna multiply that by times dropSize dot
现在将它与 dropSize.width 相乘
width cuz I'm gonna move it off.
把它移动到这里
So I just took my drop, and I made it over.
我把它创建，将它移动
And it would be in a certain spot, so
它将在某个位置上
I'm gonna create my dropView.
所以我现在创建 dropView
It's just gonna be UIView.
类型是 UIView
I'm gonna use the frame initializer here,
使用 frame 的构造器
use that frame I just created above.
上面创建的那个
I'm gonna set the dropView's background color to be UIColor
把背景颜色设置为随机的
random, another thing I added down here below.
我在下面已经添加这个方法了
Just picked one of five random colors there in my rote.
在五个里面选择一个
Notice, by the way,
主意
that when I added these extensions to UIFloat and
当我给 CGFloat 和 UIColor 添加 extension 的时候
UIColor, I made them private.
是私有的
That means only I can use them.
这表明只有我能使用它们
But it also means the name won't conflict with someone
也意味着命名不会冲突
else if someone else writes their own CGFloat dot random
如果其他人也写了一个 参数为 Int 的 CGFloat.random
that takes an int.
Theirs will work in their file, and
它们的会在它们的文件里有效
mine will work in my file.
我的会在我这里有效
Okay, so it's private to this file.
对这个文件来说它是私有的
So that's one nice thing about extensions,
这是 extension 的一个比较好的特性
you can kind of control the privacy of extensions.
你可以控制 extension 的公私有性
So there I have my dropView.
现在我有了 dropView
Now I'm just gonna add it to my gameView, addSubview.
我把它添加到 gameView 上，通过 addSubview
We really haven't had you doing addSubview.
我们之前还没用过 addSubView
But cuz you've been doing all the views in your storyboard.
因为之前都是在 stroyboard 中添加视图
But in your homework you're going to be adding your
但在作业中，你将使用 addSubView
bricks, views, and all that stuff, using addSubview.
来添加砖块，视图之类的视图
Probably your storyboard's just going to be
也许你的 storyboard
completely blank.
会是完全空白的
Or maybe you might have the score and
也许你还有显示分数
some other things in there.
和其他东西
But the bricks and the paddle, and ball,
但是砖块和球之类的东西
that's all going to be added.
都需要通过这种方式添加
You're gonna add with addSubview.
使用 addSubView
That's part of what this assignment is about.
这是这次作业的部分内容
So you get some experience creating and
所以你们会获得一些
adding views in code.
通过代码添加视图的经验
Okay? So that's what we're doing.
这就是我们在做的事情
So let's go see what this looks like.
让我们看看效果
Hopefully when we tap we'll get a random square along
希望在点击过后
the top of our view here.
一个方块会出现在顶部
So tap, we got one.
所以点击，有了一个
Good, we're getting them.
好的，我们已经做到了
So here I'm tapping them, this is great.
我一直点击，很棒
Okay, so we're adding these things along the top,
我们已经在顶部添加了这些
now I'm gonna add gravity.
现在我来添加重力效果
Okay, I'm going to add a gravitational field, and
添加一个重力场
it's going to apply to all these things.
它会适应所有的物体
It's going to pull them all down to the bottom of
会将它们拉到屏幕的底部
the screen.
Okay?
So these all will just fall down.
它们都会掉落下来
Turns out this very, very easy to do, okay?
然而实现起来很简单
All I need to do is create a gravitational field so
创建一个重力场
I'm going to say, let gravity equal a UIGravityBehaviour.
let gravity = UIGravityBehaviour
Okay, so boom, I have a UIGravityBehavior.
boom，我有了一个 UIGravityBehavior
I'm gonna take the default magnitude and direction which
默认的方向是向下
is down, at a thousand points per second per second.
速度是1000点/秒/秒
So that's perfectly fine to me.
对于我来说不错
Of course I also need a dynamic animator.
当然我还需要一个 dynamic animator
Okay?
So I'm going to create a dynamic animator here.
在这里创建一个
Now, I wanna say this, referenceView is gameView.
设置它的 referenceView 为 gameView
Okay? But I'm not gonna
但是现在这种
be able to do this.
方式不行
Now, a lot of you tripped into this, on your, assignments.
好多人都在作业里被这一点困住了
I saw on Piazza, a lot of questions about this.
我看到 Piazza 上有好多关于这个的问题
You're, like, oh, what, what's going on here?
到底发生了什么？
And you click this warning, and it says,
点击一下错误
gameView is not a part of.
它说
DropitViewController, of course it is, it's right here.
gameView 不是 DropitViewController 的一部分，当然是，它就在这里
What the heck is going on?
到底发生了什么？
And hopefully all of you have figured out that
希望你们都发现了
the reason that's happening is because
发生这种错误的原因是
I'm in the middle of initializing here.
我在构造
Okay, this is initializing this variable.
这里在构造这个变量
And you cannot access your own properties and
但你不能在这里引用属性和方法
methods until you're fully initialized.
直到你被完整构造出来
So obviously, you can't access them while you're
所以显然
initializing, by definition, so that's the problem.
在这里你不能引用 gameView，这是个问题
So, how do I get out of this conundrum?
怎样能去掉这个错误
Because UIDyanmicAnimator needs this game view
因为 UIDyanmicAnimator 需要这个 gameView
as its reference.
作为引用
Well, one thing is, I could make this an optional and
我可以把它设置为 optional
set to nil, and then the view did load, when I know that's
在 viewDidLoad 方法中
set I could set the, I could create the animator there.
创建 animator
Yeah, you could do that.
你可以这样做
Another way to do it is using a lazy.
另一种方式是使用 lazy
Variable. So
I'm gonna make this var lazy and I'm gonna set its initial
把这个变量变为 lazy
value equal to the result of executing a closure.
把它的初始化变为一个闭包的执行结果
Okay.
So, this is not gonna happen,
这里不会调用
this is not going to get initialized,
这里不会初始化
until someone actually asks for this animator.
知道某人引用这个 animator
And once they ask for it, I'm gonna execute this closure
一旦别处引用，这个闭包将被执行
by just having the closure with parentheses.
这个带括号的闭包
It takes no arguments, so I just call it with parentheses.
没有参数，所以只要有括号就可以
And it's going to execute this closure.
它将会执行这个闭包
Now, this closure better return a UIDynamicAnimator.
这个闭包最好返回一个 UIDyanmicAnimator
Okay, because I'm setting it equal to the result.
因为我把它设置为闭包的返回结果
And in fact, it's going to, because I'm gonna say, let
实际上
lazilyCreatedDynamicAnimator equal that, okay?
let UIDyanmicAnimator =
Now, this is inside a closure.
现在是在闭包内部
So I'm gonna want to say self.gameView, right?
所以需要添加 self
And then I'm just going to return
接着
lazilyCreatedDynamicAnimator.
返回 lazilyCreatedDynamicAnimator
Okay?
This kind of solves the problem.
解决了问题
Okay? I don't have any warnings,
没有警告
but you gotta be careful you better not call this
但是你得注意
before this gets set.
最好别在它被设置好之前调用它
Because this is going to be nill, you're
因为它会是 nil
going to have a reference view nill, your animator is
它的引用视图为 nil
going to get created with no reference view.
你的 animator 将不会有引用视图
It ain't going to work.
它不会工作的
Okay?
So you gotta be careful about when you call this.
所以在调用的时候得注意一下
Okay? When you access this property.
当你引用这个属性的时候
So I'm not gonna act as this property until I
所以在 viewDidLoad 之前，我不会引用这个变量
get to viewDidLoad, cuz then I'll know
因为我知道
that this outlet right here has been set.
这个 outlet 已经被设置好了
Okay?
So let's go ahead and do viewDidLoad, in fact.
现在来实现 viewDidLoad
So in viewDidLoad, all I'm gonna do is.
在这里需要做的是
Say animator, add behavior gravity.
animator.addBehavior(gravity)
So now, I have a gravitational field,
所以现在，我有了重力场
I've added it to an animator, so an animator is now going to
把它添加到了 animator 里，所以 animator 现在会
be animating the behavior of items in there.
发动里面所有的特性
The only thing I need to do is say
我在这里只要指明
which items are affected by gravity.
哪个物体被重力影响
So I'm gonna go right down and
所以到这里
say, gravity add item, my drop view.
gravity.addItem(dropView)
Now the instance I say this, the instancy animator,
这个 animator 的实例
the instance the behavior gets added to the animator, all
behavior 被添加到了 animator 中
items in that gravity field are going to start animating.
所有 gravity 中的物体都会开始动画
Now I can add those items later and then they'll start
添加了之后，它们就会动画
animating, I can take them out and it'll stop animating.
移除了之后，它们就会停止
It's all instantaneous, okay.
这些都是瞬间发生的
So if I run now, since I have an animator and
如果现在运行，我有了 animator 和
a gravitational field and
重力场
I put the items in there, they fall, okay.
我把方块放进去，它们就会掉落
Now they're accelerating.
它们在加速
See how they're getting faster and faster at the bottom?
它们会在底部变得越来越快
They're accelerating due to gravity and
这是因为重力
I can have as many of them as I want.
我可以添加任意多个
Okay and they will accelerate.
它们都会加速
They'll all be accelerating their own
它们都会以自己的
gravitational acceleration.
重力加速度加速
Okay now this is great except for
都不错，只是
they're just falling off the end and they're gone.
它们掉出了屏幕
And really what I want is for them to stay on screen.
我想要它们呆在屏幕上
So I'm gonna create a collision behavior where
所以我添加碰撞属性
the edges of my reference view here are going to.
在屏幕的底部
Stop these things and they are gonna bounce off okay?
这会使得它们停在那里，并弹起
So they are going to collide, again really easy to do,
它们将会碰撞，很容易实现
I'm just gonna go up here and create a collision behavior.
在上面，创建一个碰撞特性
I'm gonna do these same thing here and
和这里完成的工作一样
do a lazy version of this and
一个 lazy 版本的
I'll show you why I'm doing that.
你们也知道为什么要这样做
I'm gonna call it my collider.
起名为 collider
It's a UI collision behavior.
类型为 UICollisionBehavior
I'm gonna set it equal to executing a closure.
把它设置为闭包执行的结果
I'll say let my lazilyCreatedCollider
let lazilyCreatedCollider
equal UICollisionBehavior.
= UICollisionBehavior
Okay?
And.
Then, oops.
哦
Don't want that there cuz I'm not creating it there.
不在这里加括号，因为不在这里创建
There we go.
好了
So, now, the reason I did this is not because I have this
我没有调用那个构造器
reference view problem or anything like that.
是因为
It's just that I wanna configure this thing.
我想设置一下它的某些属性
Okay?
And one thing I wanna configure here is
其中一个是
that I want it to translate the reference bounds.
把屏幕的边界变为边界
Into a boundary.
That means the edges of my reference view are going to
这意味着 referenceView
be a boundary.
将会变为边界
So, anything, any items that are in this collider will
在这个 collider 中的任何物体
bounce off of that, those bounds.
都会在边界弹起来
Okay?
And now I'll return.
然后，返回它
So here you can see two different reasons.
所以你可以看到利用闭包使用 lazy
That I've used for using this lazy with the closure.
有两种不同的原因
One is,
一个是
there was something I couldn't access during initialization,
在构造期间有一些东西不能饮用
another one is I wanted to initialize some state, okay?
另一个是构造完毕后设置它的一些属性
Those are both valid reasons to do this lazy business.
这些都是使用 lazy 的正当理由
Okay?
So, I need to add that to the animator.
我需要把它添加到 animator 中
Collider and of course I need, if I want these drops
如果我想让这些方块碰撞
to collide, they need to be added to the collider as well.
需要将他们放入 collider 中
Okay?
And that's it.
好了
That's all, again, this stuff is amazingly simple,
这些东西非常精简
you just add the behaviors and things will start behaving.
你只需要添加 behavior 就会起作用
Okay? So let's watch.
看看效果
What happens here.
发生了什么
So we drop one in.
掉落一个
Oh see?
看到了吗
Bounce at the bottom.
在底部弹起
Didn't bounce very much, it's not a very big bounce, but
没弹起很高，但是它
it did bounce.
的确弹起来了
We're gonna make it bounce some more in a minute here.
一会我们会让它弹地高一点
But again, if I send a whole bunch of them down,
如果多掉落一些
not only do they bounce off the bottom,
它们不止会在底部弹起
they'll bounce off of each other a little bit, too.
它们之间也会这样
And they also can rotate.
它们也可以旋转
So if I send too many of them down here, and
如果我掉落太多
if they're getting a little, oh, look.
它们就会
Oh no!
哦
Okay, oh no, it's collapsed.
发生跌落了
Okay, so these things are allowed to tilt and rotate and
这些东西都会倾斜，旋转
they can all just collapse and fall down.
跌落
Okay?
Cuz that's the physics of them.
这是它们的物理属性
When they bounce, they might hit a little ledge and
当弹起的时候，可能会碰到边角
boom, since they can rotate, they'll tilt and tip over.
旋转，倾斜
Okay?
All right, so that's that.
就是这样
Now what if I had my game here, and I wanted to not
如果我的游戏是这样
have them tilt like that, I wanted them to stay in their
我不想让它们倾斜
nice neat rows, and also I want them to bounce more.
我想让它们在列中直直地排列，而且弹起更高
I don't want such a little tiny bounce,
现在的弹跳太不给力了
that's not very exciting.
一点也不爽
I want a big old bounce okay?
我需要一个大跳！
Off each other and off the bottom.
在它们之间还有屏幕底部
So how would I do that?
怎样实现呢？
Well I would add a dynamic item behavior that we
我可以添加一个 behavior
talked about in lecture, but it started to get the point
但是现在 behavior 太多了
here where I have an awful lot of different behaviors acting
这些 behavior 都在这些方块上起作用
on each of these drops.
So this is the time where I'm probably like,
所以，我现在想
I wanna create my own dynamic behavior that is a composite
创建一个自己的 dynamic behavior
of all these things.
把所有的东西添加到那里边
The collider, the gravity,
碰撞，重力
and the bounciness and the don't rotate.
弹跳，不旋转等等
All that, so I want it all kind of in one thing.
把所有的东西放入其中
So, let's do that.
动手实现吧
We'll just do that by creating a new file here.
创建一个新文件
New > File.
And it's a Cocoa Touch class.
Cocoa Touch 类
It's gonna be a UIDynamicBehavior subclass,
UIDynamicBehavior 子类
okay?
I'm gonna call it.
起名为
DropitBehavior, because that's what it is.
DropitBehavior
It's the behavior for these Dropit things.
它是给 Dropit 提供 behavior
So I could call DropitBehavior.
所以起名为 DropitBehavior
I could maybe call it DropBehavior,
也可以起名为 DropBehavior
I like it DropitBehavior,
但是我喜欢 DropitBehavior
cuz it's really the behavior of my whole,
因为它是为我这个 Dropit 游戏
all the things participating in my Dropit game here.
提供 behavior 的东西
So here's a DropitBehavior.
这就是 DropitBehavior
Doesn't have anything in it to start.
没有什么东西
And all I'm gonna do is basically take
我现在将这些东西
these things like gravity and collider.
gravity 和 collider
Out of here, okay, and put him over in here like that.
取出来，放到这里
Oops, sorry.
抱歉
And then I'm going to override init from UIDynamicBehavior,
然后，重写 UIDynamicBehavior 的 init 方法
right?
This is a subclass of UIDynamicBehavior.
这是 UIDynamicBehavior 子类
So I'll call super init.
所以在 init 中调用 super.init
And then all I'm gonna do is add child behaviors for
在这里调用 addChildBehavior
gravity.
参数是 graviry
And add a child behavior for the collider.
然后是 collider
Okay, so now that I've added these behaviors,
现在我添加了这些 behavior
now my dropit behavior behaves like those things do combined.
我的方块是这个 behavior 的结合
Okay?
Cuz they're children behavior of me.
因为这是我的子特性
So this is a awesome way to create a powerful behavior
这是创建强大 behavior 的一种很好的方式
just by taking other powerful behaviors.
在其中添加其他强大的 behavior 就好了
I'm also gonna have an addDrop function here,
再添加一个 addDrop 方法
that takes a drop, which is gonna be UIView, one of these
参数是一个 drop 类型是 UIView
things that we're creating, and I'm going to add the drop
在这里把它添加到
as items to both my gravity and my collider.
gravity 和 colider 的 item 中
And in fact, and
实际上
this is debatable whether this is kind of the architecture
这里也是可以探讨的
one would want, but I'm gonna actually manage the view
也就是构架的问题
whether it's in the view hierarchy or not, here.
但是我想在这里把这个 view 添加到
So I'm going to add this drop to my reference view
reference view 的子视图里
whenever you call addDrop in my behavior.
当你调用我的 behavior 的 addDrop
So I know the dynamic animator I'm in, all right,
我知道我在哪个 dynamic animator 中
because I'm a behavior.
因为我是一个 behavior
I might be nil, but might not, and
我可能是 nil 也可能不是
I know the reference view for that dynamic animator.
我知道 dynamic animator 的引用视图
That might be nil but probably not.
可能是 nil 也可能不是
And so from there, I can add SubviewThisDrop.
所以在这里，我把 drop 添加为子视图
So if you call addDrop on this drop behavior, it will add it
所以当你调用这个 drop behavior 的 addDrop 时
to the reference view and then add it to its behaviors.
它会把 drop 添加到引用视图里，然后添加到 behaviors 里面
And same thing, I could have a removeDrop.
我也可以添加一个 removeDrop 方法
All right, which takes a UI view and it does the opposite.
参数相同，做的事情相反
So, gravity.removeItem, the drop.
gravity.removeItem 参数为 drop
Collider.removeItem, the drop.
Collider.removeItem
And drop.removeFromSuperView.
drop.removeFromSuperView
Okay?
So now I have this nice class right here,
现在有了一个不错的类
which is a behavior, and
是一个 behavior
it replaces all those behavioral things over here.
它代替了这些所有
So, instead of animating behavior and
为了取代 animator 和分开的 gravity
gravity separately, I can just create a dropItBehavior
我只需创建一个 dropItBehavior
equals DropItBehavior, okay, so just create one of those.
只创建一个
And it could even probably even say let here, okay?
也可以设置为常量
And then in addBehavior,
在 addBehavior 中
I can just say add the dropItBehavior.
只需要添加 dropItBehavior
Okay? So I don't need to
我不需要再添加
add the collider separately,
collider 了
just do the drop behavior and same thing down here.
这里也是
All three of these things, adding the subview,
这里的操作
those all are just replaced by saying dropitBehavior.addDrop,
可以改成 dropitBehavior.addDrop
and the drop view.
参数为 dropView
'Kay? So you can see my
你可以看到
code here has gotten much more focused on kind of,
这里的代码变得更清晰了
what we're doing and
专注于我们的业务
the behaviors have been moved off into the behavior code.
behavior 的代码被移到了别处
Now let's run this to make sure we didn't break anything
运行测试一下
by doing that, and it looks like we're in good shape.
看起来 OK
Okay?
But these things can still tilt.
但是这些东西还是会倾斜
They're still, you know, getting out of their little
它们仍然弹出了规定列
columns, and they're also not bouncing very much.
并且也没弹那么高
So let's get back to fixing that.
回到那里，实现它
And now, whenever I wanna add a new behavior,
现在，无论何时我想添加一个新的 behavior
I'm gonna add it in this behavior class.
只要在这个类修改就可以了
So, what kind of behavior is that?
什么类型的 behavior
I'm gonna do lazy var again here.
再来一个 lazy 变量
I'm gonna call it my dropBehavior,
起名为 dropBehavior
it's a UIDynamicItemBehavior.
类型为 UIDynamicItemBehavior
Okay? I'm gonna do the same
同样的黑魔法
magical trick, it's not that magical, and
其实也没那么神奇
I'm going to say let a lazilyCreatedDropBehavior.
let lazilyCreatedDropBehavior
I'm just using this name to
起这个名字是为了
really make it clear to you what's happening here.
让你们理解这里发生了什么
It's a UIDynamicItemBehavior and I'm doing this again cuz
它的类型是 UIDynamicItemBehavior
I want to configure it just like I did for the collider.
我这样做，是想和设置 collider 一样，设置它
And so let's do it so that things can't rotate.
在这里让方块不再旋转
So one of the things you can do is allowsRotation false.
把 allowsRotation 设置为 false
'Kay?
Another thing you can do is the bounciness,
另一件事是弹跳高度
which is the elasticity.
就是 elasticity
So I'm gonna set the elasticity to about 0.75.
设置成 0.75
Elasticity of 1.0 is perfect elasticity.
设置为 1.0 是完全失重
So a thing bounces off something, it will have the
弹跳的时候
same amount of energy coming off as it had coming in, 'kay?
能量完全不损失
Perfect [INAUDIBLE], so 0.7,
完全失重
these things will eventually settle down.
0.75表示这些东西最终会安定下来
Okay? So there's that,
好了
we will return our lazilyCreatedDropBehavior
返回 lazilyCreatedDropBehavior
here.
And so all we need to do to make that work, again,
还需要做的事情是
is add it as a child behavior here.
把它添加为 child behavior
Oops, drop behavior, and
dropBehavior
also make sure that we add any drops to it aswell.
确保把 drop 也添加了
DropBehavior.addItem, the drop, and
DropBehavior.addItem 参数为 drop
same thing down here.
下面也是一样
DropBehavior.removeItem, the drop.
DropBehavior.removeItem 参数 drop
Okay?
So we don't have to change anything in the other place.
在其它地方我们不需要改变
Okay, back over here, we change nothing,
回到这里，什么也不改
because we're only changing behaviors here.
因为我们只需要改变 behavior
So this code has delegated all its behavior off to
这个代码把所有的 behavior 交给了
the dropIt behavior.
DropItBehavior
Question? >> [INAUDIBLE] How come like,
[学生提问]
we can, I guess, use the lazy variables in our init if
they're not created until init is finished, you know?
[学生提问]
>> Well, it's, so the question is how can I do this,
问题是
basically?
How am I allowed, during initialization, to, you know,
我怎么可以在初始化的时候这样做呢？
not have this set?
先不让它被设定好
And well, and the answer is,
答案是
it's a feature of the language.
这是语言的特性
It will suspend the rule that says that all things must be
它会延缓初始化的过程
initialized as long as you've set it to something that
直到你开始引用它
can be you know, determined later.
在之后初始化
So lazy variables, if they're marked lazy,
对于 lazy 变量
they don't have to be initialized at init time.
在初始化的时候，它们不需要被初始化
That's what lazy means,
这就是 lazy 的意思
does not have to be initialized at init time.
不需要在初始化的时候被初始化
But the first time someone accesses it,
直到某人引用它
it's going to be initialized, even if it wasn't a closure.
它才会被初始化，即使它不是闭包
Even if we set it to be equal to something else,
即使我们把它设置为等于其它东西
that would happen at the time someone accesses it.
它会在某人引用它的时候被创建
That's going to have to be,
这就表明
by definition, after the full initialization.
在完全初始化之后
Because no one can access any properties until full
因为在完全初始化完毕之前
initialization.
没人可以引用属性
Make sense?
听懂了吗
Okay?
If you have more questions I could cover it more, but
如果你还有问题，我也可以再说一些
that's the basic deal on the lazies.
这是 lazy 最基本的特点
Yeah?
So previous to that there were some small gaps,
[学生提问]
S and Q, sets the size of the general view to be equal to
the size of the whole content divided by like [INAUDIBLE].
[学生提问]
>> There were no gaps along top.
在顶部没有间隔
It was only when they started falling and
它只有在掉落并且
tilting a little that they made gaps between each other.
倾斜一点的时候它们之间才有间隔
Watch, okay?
看
So here, look how much springier now we are.
现在看起来多有弹性
And also notice they can't tilt, so
现在也不能倾斜了
they stay in their columns.
它们就在固定的列中
You're gonna see there's no gaps now.
之间没有间隔了
Okay, it was only the tilting that was causing them to
只有倾斜会让
have gaps.
它们之间产生间隔
So, you can send these things down,
让它们掉落
there bouncing off each other and also off the bottom.
它们会在底部和彼此之间弹跳
Okay? And they eventually
最后
settle into stasis.
它们会停下来
Okay?
Everybody got that?
每个人都懂了吗
All right? The next thing we're gonna do
下一步要做的是
in our fun game is, we're going to do a Tetris-like
做一个像俄罗斯方块一样类似的效果
thing, which is, when a row is fully clear, question?
当一行满了以后，消除
Yeah? >> Why
[学生提问]
are all the boxes completely aligned horizontally?
>> Why are they completely aligned horizontally?
它们在水平方向是对齐的吗？
>> Well, they're not.
它们不是
Like, some of them are a little higher.
有一些高一点
>> Oh, yeah, why are there slight differences?
为什么有轻微的差异
Well, I'm not a 100% sure of why that is.
我不是百分百确定
I think it's because, and don't quote me on this 100%,
我认为
but I think it's because when the thing is animating,
当它们在做动画效果是
it's not animating on integer boundaries, okay?
分界线不是整数
And I think the things can slightly overlap by tiny
它们的一小部分
fractions.
会重叠
But it's enough for
这足以让它们
one or more to draw slightly one pixel or point off.
在绘图的时候产生一个像素或点的偏差
That make sense?
有道理吧
But that's a good question.
好问题
I've noticed that as well, and
我也注意到了
it's like right in here, see those two guys right there?
看这里的这两个
Slightly different.
有轻微的不同
So yeah, good question there.
好问题
All right, back to where we were here.
回到我们这里
So what I wanna do is remove a whole row when
我想做的是
a row is complete and when my animation settles down.
当稳定下来以后，一行被填满了，把这行消掉
Okay, when my animation stops, pauses, and
当动画停止的时候
a whole row is full, I want to remove it.
一行满了，把这行去掉
Okay? So how am I gonna do that?
该怎样实现
Well, I have a nice function called removeCompletedRow
创建一个新方法 removeCompletedRow
which I'm gonna type in really fast, again, here it is.
快速输入
Don't worry about this,
别担心
you can look at this after lecture.
在课后你也可以看到这个
It's not doing anything except for looking for
它只做一些
rows that are full, and when it finds a row that's full,
寻找哪一行是满的，然后遍历这一行
it goes through and calls removeDraw.
调用 removeDrop
Right, in my dropping behavior on all of the things
对于我 drop behavior 中的
in the row.
每一个
That's all it does.
这就是它做的
Okay?
All this is just finding the ones that are all in a row, or
这是寻找一行中
that complete a row or mostly complete a row.
是满的那种情况
It allows a little bit of gaps in there.
它允许其中有一些小小的间隔
And then this just removes it.
接着，移除它
It only removes one row though.
它只会删除一行
It starts at the bottom,
从底部开始
starts going up til it finds a row and then it removes it.
找到一行删除一行
So it only does one.
一次一行
All right?
Now, how do we get this remover completed row called?
我们在哪里调用这个方法？
Okay, well,
I'm gonna call it when the animation settles down.
我将在动画停下来的时候调用
And I told you that I can find that out using my dynamic
我们可以使用 dynamic animator 的代理方法
animator's delegate.
So, here's my dynamic animator right here being created.
这是我创建的 dynamic animator
I'm actually just right here gonna say.
把它的代理
Make my dynamic animator's delegate, be myself.
设置为我自己
Okay? And of course we know that's
当然
going to cause an error.
这会引发一个错误
Right here. And that error is,
在这里
you don't implement the UIDynamicAnimatorDelegate
错误是没有实现 UIDynamicAnimatorDelegate 的协议
protocol.
So okay, no problem.
没问题
UIDynamicAnimatorDelegate.
Okay?
Problem solved.
问题解决
There's only two methods in that protocol.
协议中只有两个方法
They're both optional.
都是可选的
You don't have to implement them.
不需要都实现
The one we want is dynamicAnimatorDidPause.
其中之一是 dynamicAnimatorDidPause
See, here's the two methods.
这是这两个方法
We want this one, DidPause.
我需要这个
So when it pauses, in other words,
当它停下来的时候
it's reached stasis, for now anyway, it's gonna pause.
换句话说，停滞的时候
And when it pauses, I'm going to remove CompletedRow and
停下来的时候，调用 removeCompletedRow
that's it.
就是这样
Nothing else required.
不需要其他
So we'll see if that works.
看看有没有效果
Alright, so put a bunch of drops down here.
掉一堆方块下去
Now if it comes to stasis but there is no completed
当它停下来
row which there isn't because there's gaps in this row,
我们还没有完成一行
it does nothing.
所以它什么都没做
But if I throw some more down here, enough that it completes
再放下一些
a row, which this is going to complete a row.
完成了一行
Okay. Once it settles and pauses,
当它停下来的时候
then it will remove the drops and the other ones will fall.
它会移除这一行，其他的将会掉落下来
Okay?
Now, the two things to notice here.
有两点值得注意
One, it waited till we paused.
一，它等到完全停下来
That was cool.
这很酷
Two, after it removed them,
二，移除它们以后
everything else started animating again.
所有的东西又再次开始动画
Because nothing was underneath them.
因为它们下面没有东西
Gravity kept pulling them down and they fell.
重力使它们下坠
Okay? I didn't do anything
我什么都没做
to say keep going.
“继续”啊之类的也没有
It's just as soon as the gravity could work on those
直到重力发现它可以工作了
things, they started working.
它就会工作
Okay? It's important to notice
对于 behavior
the animator, even if it's paused,
即使动画停止了
it's always waiting for a behavior to do something.
它也在等着时机，看能不能做一些是事情
Okay?
So that's cool,
这很酷
and this happens even if I have multiple rows, so
如果我有多行
let's just make it so there's a whole bunch of rows.
多掉一些，填充多行
That are complete and
完成了
you'll see that it will remove a row and
你会发现它会先移除一行
then it will pause again and it'll just remove another row.
然后它会再次暂停，移除另一行
Okay, and you know,
你知道
depending on how many things are stacked up and
取决于这个方块是怎样罗列起来的
how it does, you'll have different response to it.
会造成不同的反应
Okay?
Now, let's go back and make it so
回到这里
they can rotate and let's see what happens again.
如果让它们可以旋转呢，会发生什么
So, how can we make it rotate?
如何让它们旋转
Trivial.
这一点
We just go back to here and just turn this,
来到这里
allows rotation, back to true, which is the default, okay?
把它改为默认的 true
And run again.
再次运行
'Kay.
So let's put a bunch of them down here again.
多掉下来一些
Now they're gonna start banging into the edges of each
它们会到处碰装
other, and they'll start rotating and
会开始旋转
bouncing around all over the place, right?
到处弹跳
But they're still filling up rows.
但它们还会填满一行
'Kay?
See? They're kinda bouncing around?
它们还会弹起
There we go.
好啦
Okay. Too big of
这中间
a gap on that last one.
间隔太大了
And if I put more down here, I'll get again.
如果再放一些，会消掉的
Okay?
Everybody cool with that?
都懂了吗
Understand what's going on there with that pausing
理解暂停那一下发生的事情
business and the fact that the animator is
还有 animator 一直试图
always trying to continue animating?
继续动画
Okay.
All right.
The next thing, I think we have time for
下一项内容，应该还有时间
both of these things, the next thing we're gonna do is
下一项
let's talk about this collider a little more right now.
我们深入讨论一下碰撞
The collider is only colliding with each other and
现在它只会彼此碰撞
colliding with the walls.
还有和墙碰撞
What if I wanna put something right, like a big,
如果我想在其中添加一个大的
I'm gonna put a circle right in the center of my.
圆形，在 view 的中间
View and have the things hit that and bounce off.
使得方块撞击它，然后弹开
So how do I create an arbitrary boundary, basically?
我怎样能够创建一个任意的边界呢
Well, the boundaries are created using bezier paths,
可以通过 berizerpath 来创建边界
as I said.
And you can create a boundary,
你可以创建一个边界
it doesn't have to have any graphical representation.
它不有任何图形代表
So, in fact, I'm gonna start by doing that.
现在开始
So I'm gonna go to my drop it behavior right here.
回到这个类中
And I'm gonna make public a method, I'm gonna create
写一个共有方法
a public method to add a boundary, okay?
用它创建一个边界
So I'm gonna call it addBarrier actually cause
起名为 addBarrier
it's gonna add a barrier somewhere,
因为它会在某处
a barrier to these things coming down or whatever.
添加一个 Barrier
I'm going to call this, these things need to be named.
这个边界需要被命名
Remember I told you about the.
还记得吗
Barrier, or the boundaries.
barrier 或者是边界
They have like an integer, or a string, or whatever.
它们需要有一个 integer 或者 string 类型的名字
So I'm going to use a string to name these things.
在这里我用 stirng
So I'm going to pass in a Bezier path,
传入一个 bezierpath
and I'm going to name it.
需要起名
So I'm going to have an argument called name.
所以需要一个 name 参数
Okay? And
I'm just going to call the colliders things and
调用 collider
you're going to remove any old boundary with that name.
利用 name 参数去除之前旧的边界
And then I'm just gonna add a new boundary,'kay?
然后再添加一个新的边界
Look at that name and that path.
看这个 name 还有 path
That's all I'm doing.
这就是我在做的事情
I'm just kind of making a nice simple method here
在这里定义了一个方法
that removes the old one and adds the new one.
去掉之前旧的，然后添加一个新的
So, it only,
there's only gonna be one barrier with that name, and
它只会利用这一个名字定义一个 barrier
I can move it any time by just saying add barrier,'kay?
我可以在任何时候移动它通过调用 addBarrier
So add barrier removes the old version of it.
然后 Barrier 就可以移除它的旧版本
So that's add barrier.
这就是这个方法
[COUGH] And so.
We can put that barrier in there.
我们可以把 barrier 放在这里
Invisibly.
不可见的
Let's put it maybe in our view did layout sub views.
可以放进 viewDidLayoutSubViews 方法中
So every time we change our bounds,
任何时候改变 bounds 的时候
we'll move this barrier to the very center of that.
我们改变 barrier 到 view 的中央
So I'm going to override view did layout sub views here.
所以我在这里重写 viewDidLayoutSubViews
Super ob views did labs sub views I want it right in
super.viewDidLayoutSubViews
the center, so I'm gonna, well let's have the size of it be,
我希望它在最中间
how about the same size as a drop?
它的尺寸设置为和方块的尺寸一样怎么样
Just to be simple.
只是为了简单
Okay, I'm gonna have this barrier that I'm gonna put in
把和方块一样尺寸的 barrier
the middle be the same size as a drop.
放到 view 的中间
I'm gonna have the origin of it be.
让它的 origin
I keep this.
Let's put it in the middle, so that's a game view, bounds,
因为要放在中间，所以等于
mid-x minus the barrier's size.
gameView.bounds.midX-BarrierSize.width/2
Barrier-size dot width divided by two, and
then the game view's.
Bounds mid-Y,
minus the barriers size dot height divided by two.
gameView.bounds.midY-BarrierSize.height/2
So I'm just putting it in the middle,'kay?
把它放到中间
So let's let this UI Bezier path that we're gonna create
开始创建 UIBezierPath
just be UI Bezier path.
let path = UIBezierPath
We'll make it a circle using oval in rect,'kay, and
使用 ovalInRect 构造器
we'll make a CG rect.
创建一个 CGRect
Which is the barrier origin and the barrier size.
参数是 barrierOrigin 和 barrierSize
Okay so everybody understand I created a Besian path,
我创建了一个 bezierPaht
that's a circle right in the middle that's the same size as
是一个在屏幕中央和方块尺寸一致的
a drop, okay?
圆形
And then I'm just going to tell my dropit behavior,
然后我通知 dropItBehavior
add this barrier.
来添加这个 barrier
And we'll call this barrier.
调用这个 barrier
Let's be good coders again.
让我们成为一个好程序员！
Let's say struct.
struct
We'll call these path names.
PathNames
Static.
We'll call this one middle barrier or something.
把它起名为 MiddleBarrier
This is gonna be the string we use so here we'll go.
这将会是我们使用的 string
Path name dot middle barrier.
PathName.MiddleBarrier
Okay?
So I can add this barrier right here and
我在这里添加barrier
that's all I need to do.
这是我需要做的全部工作
Once you add the barrier, the collider is already colliding
一旦你添加了 barrier
so it's going to make things collide with it.
其他的物体就可以和它撞击
So let's see what this looks like.
让我们看看效果
Okay?
see if we can tell.
看我们能不能看出来
Oh, do you see things bouncing away from the middle there?
看到物体被从中间弹开了吗
See that?
看到了吗
[SOUND] Okay?
But it's a little bit bad because we can't see it.
有一点不好，就是我们看不到它
I'd like to see this barrier.
我想看到它
But that's an independent thing.
但是那是一个独立的东西
Seeing it versus it being there is different.
看到它和它在那里，是不同的
So to see it I'm actually gonna make my background
为了看到它
view right here.
我需要创建背景视图
Instead of being a generic UI view I'm gonna make it
这次不是一般的视图，而是
be a view that can draw Bezier paths.
可以画 bezierpath 的视图
Okay? Now,
this is surprisingly simple to do.
这也很贱但
Okay?
I'm just going to create a UI view.
创建一个 UIView 的
Subclass, UI view.
子类
I'm going to call it BezierPathsView and it's
起名为 BezierPathsView
going to basically draw as many bezier paths as you want.
你可以在上面画任意多的 bezierpath
They'll also be named, just like the boundaries are named.
这里也需要 name，就像边界有 name 一样
Okay? And
I'm going to do this by saying var bezierPaths,
var bezierPahts
these are my Bézier paths I'm going to have.
这里装我们 bezierpath
It's just going to be a dictionary with strings as
类型是 string 为 key
the keys and UIBezierPaths as the argument, okay?
UIBezierPath 为参数的字典
I'm going to, by the way,
顺便地
I haven't been doing private in the demo for expediency.
在 demo 中我还没有使用过 privte
But, again, private is important and here,
在这里，privete 是很重要的
I am going to do the right privacy.
我将使用正确的公私有属性
So now, I'm going to have a function called,
创建一个方法
what did I call it?
起名为什么来着
Add path or something like that?
addPath 之类的？
Yeah, setPath.
哦，setPath
SetPath, and it's going to take a path,
参数是 UIBezierPath 类型的
which is a UI Bézier path.
path
It's going to be optional because we're going to allow
它是可选的，因为我们可以允许你通过这个方法
you to clear out paths if you want,
清掉 path 如果你想的话
and then it's also going to let them be named.
然后需要 name 参数
And I'm just going to put it in that dictionary,
把它们放入字典中
just going to say Bézier paths.
bezierPahts[name] = path
Path sub name equals the path.
And of course, I just changed my model basically, so
刚刚改变了模型
I'm going to just setNeedsDisplay.
所以现在需要调用 setNeedsDisplay
Okay? Then, to draw this, for
画出它们
underscore path in my bezierPaths, path.stroke.
for (_, path) in bezierPahts
Okay, that's it.
path.stroke
This is the entire implementation of this view.
这是整个 view 的实现
Okay? It's just going to
它将会以
stroke them in black.
空白的方式画出
We could add colors and all this stuff, but
我们也可以添加颜色
we're just going to stroke them all in black.
但空白的就行了
This is a numeration of a dictionary,
这是个字典的遍历
hopefully you recognize that.
希望你们看出来了
I don't care what the name is here while I'm doing this,
我不管 name 是什么
I only care the name because
我需要 name 是因为
I want to keep them unique is all.
我想让它们每个都是独一无二的
Okay?
So now what I'm going to do is go back to my storyboard, and
现在回到 storyboard
instead of this being a generic view,
换掉这个一般的视图
I'm going to go to the identity inspector, and
去到 identity inspector
turn it into a BezierPathsView.
把它变成 BezierPathsView
And also in my DropIt controller over here,
在 DropIt 控制器中
I'm going to change this outlet from being a generic
把这个出口从一般的 view 改为
UIView from being a BezierPathsView.
BezierPathsView
So now the view that I'm doing all this animation is in
现在这个 view 既可以动画
can draw arbitrary Bézier paths, okay?
又能画任意的 bezierpath
Very convenient because
非常方便
I'm going to have it draw that circle.
我可以让它画圆
Okay, that circle that we're having the collider do,
在这里的圆
which is right here.
让它产生碰撞
And I can do that with one line of code.
一行代码就可以实现
I'm just going to say gameView addPath,
gameView.setPath
or setPath, the same path, and I'll use even the same name,
和上面相同的 path 和 name
PathNames.MiddleBarrier, okay.
The good thing now is every time viewDidLayoutSubview is
好的一面就是每次 viewDidLayoutSubview
called, it'll replace, you know,
被调用
it'll move it to the middle and redraw it.
它就会移动到中间然后重新绘制
Okay? So let's now take
现在看看效果
a look at this.
[COUGH] There it is.
好了
Now, we can see it.
现在能看到了
It's still a barrier,
它仍然是一个 barrier
like it was before, so something hit it, come on.
和之前一样
There we go, boom, okay?
其他东西也会撞到它
And, you know, it's a complete barrier.
它是个完整的 barrier
And it actually is along that Bézier path.
它实际上是沿着这个 bezierpath
It's not, you know, the square containing it.
而不是这个圆圈包含着它
It is actually on it.
它实际上在边缘上
So if I fill up this thing all the way to where it starts
如果我把这里填满
getting to that,
you'll start seeing them tip right up against.
你会看到它们完整地贴着它
Do you see how they pile right up against it, there?
看到了吗？
Okay?
So you can have an arbitrary Bézier path there.
所以你可以绘制任意的 bezierPath
Okay? And if I rotate.
如果我旋转
Okay, it'll put it in the middle.
它将会出现在中间
Okay, it zoomed it out a little bit but
它放大了一点
some of the things fell off the edge when I rotated that.
有一些东西在我旋转之后掉出了屏幕
Got to be careful of that in your game too.
在游戏里也应该注意一下
When you rotate,
当你旋转的时候
if your bouncing ball is not in the middle area then,
如果你的球不在屏幕的中间部分
it's going to be outside the boundary and so
它会跳出边界
it's going to fly off into outer space forever, okay?
它会一直飞，飞到外太空的
Okay, so that's how we do barriers.
我们就是这么处理 barrier 的
And you're going to have your bricks are going to
你们也会创建砖块
be probably not round,
也许不是圆形的
well they could be round if you want, and you can put as
如果是圆的也可以
many of these little barriers as you want up here, okay?
你可以放任意多个障碍物在上面
And when you hit one of these, that delegate method,
当你击中其中一个的时候，代理方法
you're going to set yourselves a collision delegate.
你需要先设置代理
I don't really have time to do that, but,
我没有时间演示了
you know, you could make it do something, flash or
但你你可以制造一些效果
animate, whatever is required by the required tasks.
闪或者动，作业的一部分内容
Okay, the last kind of behavior I'm going to show you
最后一个 behavior 我要介绍给你们的是
is an attachment behavior.
attachment behavior
So, the way I'm going to do this attachment,
使用它的方式是
let me show you here, is when a drop comes down,
当方块掉落下来
I'm going to be able to grab onto it with
我会抓住它
a piece of string, or more like a metal rod.
就像抓住一跟金属棒一样
Grab onto it and I can move it around, okay?
抓住它到处移动
Swing it around in a circle and let it fly if I want.
让它转圈，或者让它飞走
So, that's what I'm going to do.
我将会这样实现
I'm going to do that with an attachment behavior.
利用 attachment behavior
I'm just going to create an attachment from where I start
先在拖动手势进行的时候
my pan to the middle of the drop, the currently
创建一个 attachment behavior 在方块中间
dropping drop, or the last dropped drop, basically.
正在掉落的或者最后一个掉落的
And then as I pan around,
在我滑动的时候
I'm just going to move the anchor point.
我会移动它的锚点
And because animation is all happy instantaneously, it's
因为动画发生在瞬间
just going to all magically animate to adapt to the fact
所以所有的动画都会神奇般地随着我改变它
that I'm moving the anchor point of this attachment.
的锚点而有效果
Okay?
And all the other behaviors are still going to work on it,
其他的 behavior 还是会有效
the gravity, the collisions,
重力还有碰撞
all still going to work on that thing.
都会起作用
The attachment's just going to be another behavior.
连接是另外一个特性
Now I'm going to put this attachment in the controller
我会在控制器里添加这个attachment
right here instead of in the behavior, just so
而不是在 behavior 中
you can see it all happening a little better.
这样你们看得效果更好
So let's do this kind of in multiple steps here.
这中间有几步过程
Let's go ahead and do the gesture first.
先添加手势
Okay, so to do the behavior, I need an attachment behavior,
为了实现这个 behavior，我需要一个 attachment behavior
so I'm going to create an attachment behavior here,
所以我需要在这里创建一个 attachment behavior
UI attachment behavior.
类型是 UIAttachmentBehavior
Now, this one's going to be an optional because I only have
它是可选型的，因为只有我在
this attachment when I'm panning.
拖动的时候才会有这个属性
Okay? I don't have this attach,
我没有这个 attach
it's nil basically, if I'm not currently attached to
它是 nil 的，如果我没拖着什么到处晃
something and panning around, whereas the dropping behavior
然而 drop behavior
is happening all the time.
会一直存在
Okay?
Again, I could put this attachment behavior
我可以把 attachment behavior
in the dropping behavior.
放在 drop behavior 里
I could do that.
我可以这么做
I'm not going to, for kind of seeing it on screen,
但我不会这么做
the code on screen issue, but I could put it over there.
把它放到这里看起来更清楚
So I'm going to put it here.
所以我把它放到这里
So I have this attachment.
所以我有了 attachment
We're going to have to do some things with this attachment in
一会儿再对这个 attachment 做些事情
a second, but let's just say we have this attachment.
但是现在我们已经有了这个 attachment
Let's go add that pan gesture.
现在添加拖动手势
Okay, so we'll go over here, we'll go to our storyboard.
去到 storyboard
Here's our storyboard right here.
这里就是
Let's go down and find pan.
找到 pan
Where is it?
在哪呢
Pan? Right here.
在这
So let's add pan to this thing.
给它添加 pan 手势
Here's pan in the document outline.
在 document outline 有 pan
Let's go ahead and
现在为 pan gesture
put the pan gesture down here by the drop gesture, I guess.
设置出口
Okay, put her right there, okay,
放到这里
it's an action, we'll call it grabDrop.
它是一个 action，起名为 grabDrop
Okay, because that's what it's going to do,
这就是它将要做的事情
it's going to grab onto a drop okay, here it is.
它将会捕获一个方块
All right that's all we need to do in our UI here.
在 UI 这里只需要做这些工作
Let's go back to our drop the controller.
回到控制器中
All right, so how are we going to implement this grab drop?
我们将如何实现这个方法呢
All right, we have that attachment,
我们有了 attachment
basically all we need to do is, when we first start
我们需要做的时
our gesture, we need to create that attachment.
当手势开始的时候，创建 attachment
Then as it moves,
移动的时候
we're just going to move that anchor point.
改变锚点的位置
And when it ends,
结束的时候
we're going to set the attachment back to nil.
把 attachment 设置为 nil
So, this is incredibly easy to do.
实现起来很容易
You're finding all this, I hope,
希望你们都理解
to be pretty straightforward to do.
这很容易理解
It's a pretty amazing and powerful system.
iOS 是个非常强大的系统
But in this hand gesture, first,
在 pan gesture 中
I'm going to get the point.
首先，获取点
Okay? The gesture point,
手势的点
that is just the sender's location in our gainView.
它就是 sender.locationInView 参数为 gameView
All right, so now I know where that pan is.
所以现在我知道了手势在哪里
And I'm just going to switch on what state we're in with
现在我需要判断这个手势
this gesture.
所处的状态
And if we're in began, so if the thing just began,
如果刚开始
then I'm just going to create the attachment.
我们需要创建这个 attachment
So I'm going to say attachment equals UIAttachmentBehavior.
attachment = UIAttachmentBehavior
Now, here's all the ways you can attach things.
这里是所有的构造方法
You can attach between two items, between an item and
你可以在两个物体之间连接，在一个物体和一个锚点上连接
an anchor.
You can even attach between two items or
你也可以连接一个物体
an anchor with offset from the center, which is kind of a fun
以及一个锚点中心的偏移，这个很有趣
one because if it can rotate, then as it spins around,
因为它可以旋转
it will be spinning around because the attachment's not
attachment 并不是死死地
dead in the center, right?
呆在原点
It's right off onto the side.
它会在边上有一个偏移
It's not in the middle of the square.
不会再方块的中间
It might be in the corner and so it kind of rotates.
它也许在角落，所以可以旋转
So that's kind of fun.
还是很有趣的
But, we're just going to do to the center here.
在这里我只会实现在中间的
And so, we need to attach the item.
我们需要 attach 物体
So we want this one right here to the anchor.
我们选择这个 attachedToAnchor
This is the one we want.
这是我们需要的
So the item, what item are we attaching to?
item，我们需要 attach 什么东西
Well, we're attaching to the last.
我们将要 attach 最后一个
DroppedView.
掉落的方块
So I'm gonna have to create a LastDroppedView,
我会创建一个 LastDroppedView
which will have to go implement.
一会儿实现
And what anchor?
哪一点？
Well, I'm gonna anchor it to the gesturePoint, 'kay?
把它设置为手势的那一点
Wherever that pan gesture is.
手势在哪，那一点就在哪
So let's do this lastDroppedView.
现在来处理 lastDroppedView
That's easy.
这很简单
We'll just say var lastDroppedView.
创建 lastDroppedView
It's a UIView that can be nil if we're not currently
类型是 UIView，它可以使 nil 如果现在还没有
dropping.
掉落的
And then down here in drop or we drop something,
在这里，掉落的时候
I'm just gonna say that the lastDroppedView equals to
把 lastDroppedView 等于
the dropView.
dropView
'Kay, so I'm just keeping track of the lastDroppedView.
所以我在跟踪这个 lastDroppedView
'Kay, that make sense?
能说得通吧
An exclamation point, yeah.
一个感叹号
No, we don't want that.
不，我不要这样
We want to say.
我们...
And actually, I guess we'll always have last drop view.
实际上，我认为我们会一直拥有 lastDropView
This is the kind of one where it's like, if let there, or
这里应该使用 if let
do I just wanna do it.
或者直接解包
Actually, I'm just gonna if let.
实际上我会使用 if let
I just wanna be careful here in case for
我想在这里小心一点
some reason the last drop view isn't around.
以防这个 lastDropView 不存在
So I'm gonna say if we can let the viewToAttachTo equal
if let viewToAttachTo =
the lastDroppedView,
lastDroppedView
then we will start this attachment business.
然后我会开始 attachment 的创建
'Kay, it'll be safe there, because we might change
现在这里安全了
something in the future where we don't always set the last
因为我们可能再以后
drop view to something, so I wanna be careful there.
不总是设置 lastDropView，所以需要小心点
[COUGH] So, we have the attachment.
所以现在有了 attachment
By the way, I'm also gonna put a feature of my game that once
游戏中还会添加一个特性
you grab onto something, you can't grab onto it again.
如果你抓住了某个东西，你不能再次抓住它
Like, if you grab onto it and let it go.
如果你抓住了它，然后放手
I'm not gonna let you grab onto it again because I might
我不会再让你抓住它
wanna eventually turn this into a game where you have to
因为我想把这个游戏变成
like, line the things up into perfect stacks or
把这些方块排成一列
something like that, and
之类的
so I can put something in here like this to make my
增加的这个特性
game a little more challenging where I can't constantly be
让游戏更有挑战性一点
just regrabbing it until I get exactly where I want, okay.
我不能一直松开抓住，直到调整为我想要的地方
So that's it.
好的
All I have to do in began is create that attachment and
在 .began 只需要做这些事情
then if things change.
如果手势改变了
[SOUND] All I have to do is change that anchor point.
我需要做的只有改变锚点
That's the attachment's anchorPoint, and
这是 attachment 的锚点
if the attachment is nil, this will just do nothing.
如果 attachment 是 nil，这什么都不会做
That's fine.
这没关系
So that's the gesturePoint.
这是 gesturePoint
And when it's all over, 'kay, the span is just gonna say
当手势结束的时候
attachment equals nil, [COUGH] okay?
把 attachment 设置为 nil
All done.
完成
So, and of course, we have the default case,
当然，还有 default
all the things like the Pan failed or
手势不完整等等
whatever, I'm just gonna do nothing in that case.
在这个 case 什么都不做
That's probably not,
其实也不是
actually, I probably should be doing something here if,
如果我在一个手势的中间
like if I was in the middle of this and
突然间一个电话打进来了
a phone call came in and my Pan failed,
手势没有完成
I probably should be doing attachment equals nil.
我也许应该把 attachment 设置为 nil
'Kay, so probably attachment equals nil should be
所以在 default 中
the default case, but I haven't really analyzed that.
应该吧 attachment 设置为 nil，但我没有分析过
I haven't done that full design, but
我没有做完整的设计
that's something you obviously wanna think about if you're
如果你们需要搭建什么，这些东西
building something.
是你需要考虑的
Okay, [COUGH] now this attachment we're creating it,
好的，attachment 创建完了
but notice we never added to the dynamic animator.
但我们没有把它添加到 dynamic animator 里
So this attachment is not ever actually going to be animated.
所以这个 attachment 不会有效果
So where we're gonna do that, I'm actually gonna do that in
应该在哪里处理呢
the will set and did set of the attachment.
应该在 attachment 的 willSet 和 didSet 里
So in the will set, 'kay, that's this
在 willSet 中
attachment is about to be set to something new, I'm gonna
attachment 需要设置到新的物体上了
tell my animator to remove the existing attachment.
我要告诉 animator 把存在的 attachment 去掉
So if there's an attachment behavior that's existing right
如果现在上面有一个 attachment behavior
now, remove it, and similarly, as long as [COUGH] I
删掉它
am setting this to non-nil, if attachment is at nil, okay, so
在 didSet 中
if the attachment is not nil, then,
如果 attachment 不是 nil
my animator can have the behavior of the attachment.
我的 animator 就可以拥有这个 attachment 特性
Okay, this is getting pretty bad, okay.
这里有点错误
Got it?
明白了吗？
Sorry about that.
抱歉
So, get that?
明白了？
What I'm doing there?
我在这里做了什么
I'm basically adding and removing from the animator as
在 attachment 被设置的时候
the attachment is set, or not set.
我只在 animator 里添加和删除了 attachment
Now, we can go ahead and run this now, and I'm going to,
现在开始运行程序
we're not gonna be able to see it though,
但是现在还看不到连接
because we're not setting any Bezier path in our view, but
因为我们没在 view 中设置 bezierpath
let's go ahead and look at it, see what it looks like.
但是我们看看效果
Okay, so here's a drop.
掉落一个
I grabbed it.
抓住它
Okay, so if you can kind of imagine,
想象一下
I can even like, balance it on it's little stick.
就像把它放在一个棍上，让它保持平衡
>> [LAUGH].
>> So you can see I'm at there.
所以你们能看到，我在这里
And if I let it go, or I can just bounce it off this thing.
如果甩动它，让它撞击这个
'Kay, it's still attached.
它仍然连接着
All right, see that.
好的
And I can let it go, and it'll bounce, 'kay?
我松手，它仍然会弹跳
I can grab the next one.
我可以抓住下一个
Now, it would be nicer if we could see this
如果能看到
little attachment wire that's on here, right?
它们之间的连线就好了
And we can, because we have this nice view that makes it
我们也可以这么做
easier to show a path.
因为我们的 view 让显示 bezierPath 更容易
So really,
what we need to do is we just need to say let path equal
let path = UIBezierPath
UIBezierPath, and then we just need to say gameView,
gameView.addPath
addPath, this path, which we're gonna have to create,
我们创建的这个 path
and then again, we need a name for it, so
我们还是需要一个 name
we'll call this the attachment path name.
我们给它起名为 Attachment
Attachment, like that, 'kay, so a pathNames.Attachment.
PathNames.Attachment
'Kay, so really all we need to do is create
我们需要做的就是创建这条
that path in here.
BezierPath
'Kay, the path between the attachment point and
attachment 点和
the set path.
抱歉，setPath
[SOUND] Okay, we just need to create this path,
我们只需要创建这个 path
that goes from the attachment anchor point,
从 attachment 的锚点
to the middle of the view.
到 view 的中间点
Well, okay, we need to find that view.
我们需要先找到这个 view
So, how do we get the view?
我们怎么能找到呢
All behaviors, most of them anyway
所有的 behavior，基本都
can tell you the items that they're currently animating.
基本都可以告诉你它们正在 animate 的东西
All right, they're affecting the behavior of and
attached behavior 可以
attached behaviors can do that.
获取得到
[SOUND] So, I'm gonna say if the attachedView equals and
if attachedView =
how am I gonna get it?
如何获取呢
I'm gonna get it by asking the attachments for its items.
获取 attachment.items
That's all the things that it is attaching, could be two
这是它正在连接的所有东西
items, could be one item, in our case gonna be one.
可以使两个也可以是一个，在这里是一个
Since it's one I'm just gonna get the first one.
因为它只有一个，所以我获取第一个
First is a array method, 'kay?
first 是一个数组的方法
And I'm gonna make sure that it's UIView,
我要确保它是个 UIView
it's going to be UIView, but, I'm gonna
它也会是一个 UIView
make sure it's a UIView so I'm gonna do if let here, 'kay?
但是我得确保，所以在这里进行 if let
So now I know that I've got the attached view that's going
所以我获取到了连接到的视图
on, it's in here.
在这里
So now I can make a connection between these two things.
所以我现在可以在它们之间做一个连接
I can just say path.moveToPoint,
path.moveToPoint
I'll move to the anchor point, so that's the attachment's
移动到锚点，attachments 的锚点
anchorPoint, and then I'm going to path.addLineTo, and
接着，path.addLienTo
I'm just going to add a line to the attachedView's center.
然后把连接视图的中心点传进去
'Kay, so we got that.
所以我们获取到了
The only thing about this is,
但出现的问题时
this is only going to work once.
这只会调用一次
When did set happens of the attachment.
在 attachment 的 didSet 发生的时候
When I first create that thing it's gonna draw that line,
当第一次创建它的时候，这条线会出现
that's great but what if line of that moving it around?
但是在移动的时候呢
'Kay, when I move it around the anchor point moves so
当我移动的时候，锚点移动了
this is gonna be no good anymore.
所以这就不好了
So, I actually have to put this code inside of
所以我需要把这些代码放到
the attachment's action, 'kay?
attachment.action 里
So the action is just closure, once we put it inside
action 就是一个闭包
a closure we're gonna have to do self dots in here.
所以我们需要在这里添加 self
So we can be obvious that we are capturing self
我们很清楚，当我们这么做的时候
when we do this.
是在捕获 self
Here's another self dot that we need, and here's another
这里也需要
self dot and this we'll say question mark, okay?
这里也需要，添加问号
So here we have this action, so
所以这里我们有了这个 action
this is good, but, and this will work.
很好，这也会有效
Let's go ahead and run this.
运行起来试试看
'Kay, so grabby dots so you can see it works, right.
抓住一个，可以看到它起作用了
It's showing the connection there, but
它显示了连接
it doesn't clean up.
但是它没有被清理
That's no good, 'kay?
这就不好了
And so what's going on here?
发生了什么
'Kay, let's fix two problems.
让我们一起改 bug
One, this cleanup, is no good.
一，这里需要清理
That's just because in will set right here,
这是因为在 willSet 里
we need to tell our gameView to
我们需要告诉 gameView
set that path to nil, for that name, the path name.
把 path 设置为 nil，对于这个 pathName
Attachment, right?
这个 attachment
Every time we set a new one, we need to delete the old one.
每一次我们设置一个新的，我们需要删除旧的
The other thing is we got the memory cycle problem here.
另一个问题是，在这里有了内存的循环引用
[SOUND] Right?
对吧
Because this attachment, which self points to, so
因为 self 指向 attachment
self points to attachment.
Attachment has the action.
attachments 有 action
The action points back to self, 'kay?
在 action 中又指向了 self
'Kay, here's to using it here the attachment itself.
在这里又指向了自己
But it's pointing back to self, so
但是它指向了它自己
we got a memory cycle here.
所以我们有了循环引用
So we have to say, that inside here, self,
所以在这个闭包里
should be unowned, in this closure, 'kay?
self 应当为 unowned
And that means that the system will not
这表明，系统不会为了这个闭包有效
keep self in memory in order to make this closure work.
而一直把 self 留在内存里
It will assume the self is always gonna be there,
它将会假设，self 是一直存在的
which it is always gonna be, because if there's no self,
其实它也是一直存在的
there's no attachment.
因为没有 self 就没有 attachment
If there's no attachment, there's no action, so
没有 attachment 就没有 action
then there's no closure, 'kay?
当然也就没有闭包了
So we broke that memory cycle here.
所以在这里打破了循环
All right, so that fixes both of these problems.
问题都改好了
So here we go,
跑起来
drop one, swing it around, well, bang it on here.
掉下来一个，旋转它
Woops.
哦~
Like that.
像这样
Let go.
松手
'Kay, put a whole bunch of these down here.
多放几个
'Kay, now notice that it, let's say I have enough of
我们注意到
these things to make a row disappear, but
我们有足够多的东西来让一行小时
if I drag onto this and I'm animating, see, the row won't
如果我拽住一个
disappear because we're never coming to stasis here, 'kay?
行不会消失，因为没有到稳定的状态
But if I let it come to stasis,
但如果我让它稳定下来
then we don't have a complete row.
我们还没有完整的一行
Okay, let's get it clear row.
让它清除一行
[SOUND] There we go.
好的
We got one, 'kay?
我们有了一行
So now we got a complete row there,
有了一个完整的一行
the third one up from the bottom.
倒数第三行
And as long we do this, it's not gonna come to stasis,
只要我们这样做，它就不会是稳定状态
not gonna pause, not gonna do it,
不会暂停，不会消除
but if we let go, settles down, now it'll do, 'kay?
如果我们松手，安定下来，现在就会消除了
All right, so that's it for that demo.
demo 做完了
I should got to show you a lot of different behaviours there.
我应该展现给你许多不同的 behaviour
I didn't show you push behaviour,
我还没有展示 push
which you're gonna need for your assignment.
你们作业中需要使用到
I didn't show you snap behaviour which is very
还有 snap
commonly used in the UI, but you don't need it for
在 UI 中非常常用
your assignment, so I didn't show that one, but
但是作业中不需要，所以我没展示
I showed you the collider and the gravity.
但是我展示了 collider 还有 gravity
The gravity is an optional one in your assignment, you might
在作业中 gravity 是可选的
wanna use gravity, it could be fun, totally up to you.
你可以使用，会很有趣，根据你来
[SOUND] But that's it.
好的
So, good luck with assignment five, and
祝你们作业完成地愉快
if you have any questions, I'll be here as usual.
如果有问题，过来找我
>> For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.